<Group id="itunes"> 
<title>iTunes</title>          
<description> With iOS 5, use of iTunes is no longer a prerequisite for
deployment of iOS devices. However, iTunes supports the ability to back up data
from iOS devices. If a backup capability is necessary, iTunes deployment in the
enterprise may be necessary. Alternatively, data could be backed up in cloud
services or users could be expected to back up iOS devices on personally-owned
systems (as in a BYOD scenario). However, legal concerns may arise regarding
the presense of enterprise data on personally-owned systems. If enterprise
deployment of iTunes is planned in order to support the ability to back up iOS
devices, it can be configured to improve its security posture. A small number
of items are also presented which are of negligible security concern, but may
be of interest to administrators who have network bandwidth or deployment
concerns. Apple provides guidance for iTunes deployment in support of iOS at:
<!-- <a href="http://help.apple.com/iosdeployment-itunes/">http://help.apple.com/iosdeployment-itunes/</a>.
<ul> <li>Settings for Mac OS X systems, and mechanisms for deploying them, are
described at:
<a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT2653">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT2653</a>
and:
<a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3490">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3490</a>.
</li> <li>Settings for Windows systems are described at:
<a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT2102">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT2102</a>.
</li></ul> -->
The following sections reference specific settings but do not provide
implementation instructions, which vary by host platform and systems management
mechanism. Most settings here also correspond to settings in the GUI, which
become “grayed-out” if administratively disabled. </description>
 
<Group id="disable_music_sharing"> 
<title>Disable Music Sharing</title>          
<description> To prevent the system from sharing music (and potentially other
files) over the local network when iTunes is running, set the
<tt>disableSharedMusic</tt> key to <tt>true</tt>. </description>
 
</Group>

<Group id="disable_ping"> 
<title>Disable Ping</title>          
<description> To prevent users from using Ping to potentially share sensitive
information, set the <tt>disablePing</tt> key to <tt>true</tt>. </description>
 
</Group>

<Group id="disable_itunes_store_if_bandwidth_constrained_"> 
<title>Disable iTunes Store (if Bandwidth Constrained)</title>          
<description> If using the iTunes store is not appropriate due to limited
bandwidth, set the <tt>disableMusicStore</tt> key to <tt>YES</tt>.
</description>
 
</Group>

<Group id="disable_radio_if_bandwidth_constrained_"> 
<title>Disable Radio (if Bandwidth Constrained)</title>          
<description> If using streaming audio is not appropriate due to limited
bandwidth, set the <tt>disableRadio</tt> key to <tt>YES</tt>. </description>
 
</Group>

<Group id="use_activation_only_mode_if_direct_connectivity_unavailable_">
<title>Use Activation-Only Mode (if Direct Connectivity Unavailable)</title>          
<description> iOS 5 permits device activation if network connectivity is
available. However, if cellular or trusted WiFi network connectivity is not
available to support device activation, iTunes can be put into a special mode
to support rapid activation of multiple devices. This is described in: 
<!-- <a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4335">http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4335</a>. -->
</description>
    
</Group>

</Group>
