<Group id="manually_configured_device_settings">
<title>Manually-Configured Device Settings</title>
<description> The following security-relevant settings can be manually applied.
These settings depend on the user’s control of the device, and thus training
users can help them make appropriate choices. </description>

<Rule id="disable_wi_fi_if_practical">
<title>Disable Wi-Fi, if Practical</title>
<description> If the iOS device is not to be connected to a Wi-Fi network,
disable Wi-Fi. Set <b>Settings &gt; Wi-Fi &gt; Off</b>. </description>
<rationale> Disabling <b>Ask to Join Networks</b> will prevent the phone from
automatically associating with previously known (but potentially-spoofed)
access points without user interaction, and should be disabled whenever
possible. Users should be instructed to use only trusted WiFi networks.
</rationale>
<ref nist="AC-18(3)"/>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_bluetooth_manually_if_practical">
<title>Disable Bluetooth Manually, if Practical</title>
<description> To disable Bluetooth, set <b>Settings &gt; Bluetooth &gt; Off</b>, when practical. </description>
<rationale> Leaving Bluetooth enabled can expose the presence of an iOS device,
although the device provides visual cues when it is in the Bluetooth
“discoverable” mode which allows it to pair with other devices. The Bluetooth
profiles supported by iOS are described at <b>http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3647</b>.
</rationale>
<ref nist="AC-18(3)"/>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_location_services_if_practical">
<title>Disable Location Services, if Practical</title>
<description> If the ability of apps and web pages to determine the location of
the device poses an unacceptable risk, disable Location Services. Set
<b>Settings &gt; General &gt; Restrictions &gt; Privacy: Location Services &gt; Off</b>. Note also that
usage of Location Service can be controlled on a per-app basis, at the user’s
discretion. Given the utility of location information for some apps (such as
Maps), user-determined settings may be most practical. </description>
<rationale> If an application (such as Maps) wishes to use Location Services
while being disabled, the user will be prompted to return to <b>Settings</b> to
enable it. </rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_loading_of_remote_images_if_practical">
<title>Disable Loading of Remote Images, if Practical</title>
<description> To disable the automatic loading of images in e-mail, set
<b>Settings &gt; Mail, Contacts, Calendars&gt; Mail: Load Remote Images &gt; Off </b>
, if this is practical. </description>
<rationale> Automatically loading images in e-mail messages can leak usage
information to authors of fraudulent e-mail. It can also provide an opportunity
for malicious images to exploit any implementation flaws in complex graphics
libraries. At the same time, this may also inhibit viewing of images that are
useful. </rationale>
</Rule>
</Group>

