<Group id="deploying_configuration_profiles">
<title>Deploying Configuration Profiles</title>
<description> After a configuration profile is created — typically in an MDM console — it must be deployed to devices. This section discusses methods available for installing a configuration profile onto an iOS device, along with their security implications.
<br />
<br />
<i>Customizing profiles to individual users implies embedding sensitive authentication information within transmitted profiles. This introduces a need for confidentiality during transmission of such files.</i></description>

<Group id="deploy_over_the_air_with_encryption_and_authentication"> 
<title>Deploy Over-the-Air with Encryption and Authentication</title>
<description> If configuration profiles will be deployed over-the-air, ensure
use of authentication and encryption.
<br />
<br />
If the iPhone can authenticate a configuration profile during its installation, the <b>Settings &gt; General &gt; Profile</b> screen will display <b>Verified</b>.
<br />
<br />
Over-the-air deployment that is authenticated and encrypted requires the
support of enterprise infrastructure, such as directory services, an enterprise
certificate trusted by iPhone, an SCEP server, and a web server. The server
component of MDM products may provide some of this infrastructure.</description> 
<rationale> Deploying configuration profiles to a device over-the-air consists
of three major steps:
<ul>
<li><i>Authentication</i> of the user, typically leveraging
existing directory services.
</li>
<li><i>Enrollment</i>, which involves the device transmitting device-specific information to the enterprise, and receiving a device certificate in return.
</li>
<li><i>Installation</i> of an encrypted, authenticated configuration profile onto the device.
</li>
</ul>
Some MDM products include a server component that provides a web-based service for users to initiate this process, while others initiate the process by requiring users to download a particular MDM client app from the App Store which can facilitate the process.
<br />
<br />
Transmission and data formats used by the MDM protocol are thoroughly standards-based. Detailed, authoritative description of the transactions between the device and the enterprise are available to Apple-registered developers at <b>https://developer.apple.com</b>.
<br />
<br />
Additional description and security analysis is available in <b>https://github.com/intrepidusgroup/imdmtools/blob/master/Presentations/InsideAppleMDM_ShmooCon_2012.pdf</b>, linked from <b>intrepidusgroup.com/insight/2012/01/changes-to-apple-mdm-for-ios-5-x/</b>.
</rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="manual_deployment_with_apple_configurator">
<title>Manual Deployment with Apple Configurator</title>
<description> Apple Configurator provides similar capabilities to the iPhone Configuration Utility, but offers enhanced ability for configuring a large number of devices for deployment. The tool is only available on the Apple platform.
<br />
<br />
One key feature of the tool is the ability to control device configuration. The Supervise capability allows an administrator to maintain control over the configuration of devices, and ties the devices to the administrator computer - preventing the device from pairing with another computer.
<br />
<br />
This trust relationship is accomplished through the use of a Supervisory Host Identity Certificate and device Escrow keybag. When paired, the host stores a certificate in the login keychain. The device Escrow keybag manages files that provide authentication of the trust relationship that was previously established with the host. Pairing with any other host via iTunes is then prevented due to the lack of a record of trust.
</description>

<rationale> Apple Configurator is a free tool that is available for download from the Apple App Store. Documentation is available at <b>help.apple.com/configurator/mac</b>. Additional information is available at <b>www.apple.com/support/ipad/enterprise</b>.
</rationale>
</Group>

<Group id="manual_deployment_with_iphone_configuration_utility"> 
<title>Manual Deployment with iPhone Configuration Utility</title>      
<description> Manually using the iPhone Configuration Utility (iPCU) is the
safest means of deploying configuration profiles to devices, but does not scale
well as it depends on administrators’ manual intervention. It also implies that
an MDM server will not be used to remotely monitor device status. Nevertheless,
transferring the profile to a device which is directly connected via USB cable
avoids threats to confidentiality and integrity inherent in network transfers.
</description>
 
<rationale> iPCU is available at <b>http://www.apple.com/support/iphone/enterprise/</b> (cryptographic checksum unavailable). Documentation is available at <b>http://help.apple.com/iosdeployment-ipcu/</b>.
</rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="avoid_unauthenticated_unencrypted_deployment_methods"> 
<title>Avoid Unauthenticated, Unencrypted Deployment Methods</title>           
<description> Avoid deployment of configuration profiles through methods that
do not provide encryption and authentication. Email is especially discouraged.
</description> 
<rationale> It is possible to distribute configuration profiles to individual
devices by emailing the profile to the user of the device or providing a link
via SMS. Once the profile is accepted by the end user, the iOS device
facilitates its installation. These methods are not recommended because they do
not generally provide authentication of the sender of the configuration
profile, or encryption of the profile itself during transmission. Users should
generally be taught not to have confidence about the origin of email
attachments or SMS messages.
<br />
<br />
Emailing configuration profiles also presupposes that the user has configured an email account on the iPhone.
<br />
<br />
Furthermore, once the configuration profile is in the receiver’s mailbox, it will remain there until it is manually deleted. If the mobile profile contains sensitive information, its prolonged existence in an unmanaged mailbox poses additional risk.</rationale>
</Group>
</Group>
