<Group id="email">
<title>Email</title>
<description> Permitting users to access only enterprise-supported email
accounts decreases the risk posed by email-based attacks. It ensures that
enterprise-provided countermeasures against email attacks (such as content
filters or anti-virus software) can scan email transmitted to the device.
</description>

<Rule id="prevent_moving_messages_between_mail_accounts">
<title>Prevent Moving Messages between Mail Accounts</title>
<description> Disable <b>Allow Move</b> for all email accounts. </description>
<rationale>Moving mail directly between accounts could permit the movement of
enterprise information to personal email accounts.  While this is possible
simply through email forwarding, in that case the enterprise email server (when
used as the MTA) has at least the possibility of logging such transfers.
</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="enable_s_mime_support_for_mail_if_needed">
<title>Enable S/MIME Support for Mail if Needed</title>
<description> Set <b>Enable S/MIME</b> to <b>Checked</b>, to provide encrypted and
authenticated email support. Ensure that transmission of
configuration profiles to devices is encrypted and authenticated if S/MIME
certificates containing private keys are embedded. The iOS device can also be
configured to use an SCEP server to retrieve S/MIME certificates for use with
Mail.</description>
<rationale>S/MIME provides the capability for users to send and receive S/MIME
email messages from wireless email devices. S/MIME and digital signatures
provide assurance the message is authentic. Without S/MIME users will not be
able to read encrypted email and will not be able to encrypt email with
sensitive information.
</rationale> 
</Rule>

<Rule id="enable_ssl_for_mail_connections">
<title>Enable SSL for Mail Connections</title>
<description> Ensure <b>Use SSL</b> is enabled for all incoming and outgoing
email accounts.</description>
<rationale>SSL provides authentication of the mail server to
which the mail client connects, and also encrypts traffic between the mail
server and the email client.
</rationale>
</Rule>

</Group>
