<Group id="mobile_device_management"> 
<title>Mobile Device Management</title>  
<description> Some behavior of Mobile Device Management (MDM) software can be
configured inside a configuration profile. This includes how much information
an MDM server can retrieve from a device, whether an MDM server can update
profiles remotely, whether an MDM server can remotely wipe a device, and
whether an MDM server can reset a device’s password. These settings allow for
more fine-grained adjustment between enterprise control versus user control of
a device. Some MDM products may not permit administrators to disable some of
their capability for querying devices.  Information about enterprise deployment
using MDM is available from Apple at
<b>http://www.apple.com/ipad/business/it-center/deployment-mdm.html</b>.
</description> 

<Rule id="sign_messages"> 
<title>Sign Messages</title>          
<description> Set <b>Sign messages</b> to Checked. </description> 
<rationale> This setting causes responses generated by the device (in response
to commands from the MDM server) to be signed with the device’s identity
certificate.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28841" />
</Rule> 

<Rule id="check_out_when_removed"> 
<title>Check Out When Removed</title>          
<description> Set <b>Check out when removed</b> to Checked. </description> 
<rationale> This causes the device to send a message to the MDM server whenever
the configuration profile is removed.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28842" />
</Rule>

<Group id="access_rights_for_remote_administrators"> 
<title>Access Rights for Remote Administrators</title> 
<description> The following settings control what an MDM server is permitted to
query from an iOS device. For an enterprise-owned, enterprise-controlled
device, permitting the enterprise administrator to query as much information as
possible is appropriate. Some MDM products may simply include these access
rights by default and offer options to retrieve less information from the
device.  

<br />
<br />
At the same time, querying all of these types of information may not be
appropriate even for some enterprise users, and for enterprises that support
BYOD scenarios. The terms of any individual organization’s “BYOD Contract” with
their users is beyond the scope of this document.
</description>

<Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_general_settings"> 
<title>Allow Remote Query of General Settings</title>          
<description> In the <b>Query device for</b> section, set <b>General
settings</b> to Checked. </description>
<rationale>ALlowing an enterprise to be able to query general device settings
such as profile names and identifiers permits the enterprise to have insight
into the ownership of profiles installed onto the device.
</rationale>
<ident cce="28843" />
<ref nist="CA-9"/>
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_security_settings">
<title>Allow Remote Query of Security Settings</title>
<description> In the <b>Query device for</b> section, set <b>Security
settings</b> to Checked. </description>
<rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query security settings
permits the enterprise to have insight into the device's security posture.
</rationale>
<ident cce="28844" />
<ref nist="CA-9"/>
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_network_settings"> 
<title>Allow Remote Query of Network Settings</title>          
<description> In the <b>Query device for</b> section, set <b>Network
settings</b> to Checked. </description>
<rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query network settings
permits the enterprise to have insight into the device's network
connection capabilities.
</rationale>
<ident cce="28845" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_restrictions"> 
<title>Allow Remote Query of Restrictions</title>          
<description> In the <b>Query device for</b> section, set <b>Restriction</b> to
Checked. </description>
<rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query restrictions
enforced on the device permits the enterprise to have insight into
whether certain device behavior is configured, such as encrypted
backups.
</rationale>
<ident cce="28846" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_configuration_profiles"> 
<title>Allow Remote Query of Configuration Profiles</title>          
<description> In the <b>Query device for</b> section, set <b>Configuration
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description>
<rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query installed configuration
profiles permits the enterprise to understand the overall composed configuration
applied to the device.
</rationale>
<ident cce="28847" />
<ref nist="CA-9"/>
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_applications">
<title>Allow Remote Query of Applications</title>
<description> In the <b>Query device for</b> section, set <b>Applications</b>
to Checked. </description>
<rationale>Allowing an enterprise to query installed applications 
provides insight into the device's software inventory, which is valuable
in incident response.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28848" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_query_of_provisioning_profiles"> 
<title>Allow Remote Query of Provisioning Profiles</title>          
<description> In the <b>Query device for</b> section, set <b>Provisioning
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description>
<rationale>Allowing an enterprise to be able to query installed provisioning
profiles permits the enterprise to be aware of expiry dates
for these.
</rationale>
<ident cce="28849" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_configuration_profiles">
<title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Configuration Profiles</title>          
<description> In the <b>Add / Remove</b> section, set <b>Configuration
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description>
<rationale> Allowing an enterprise to add or remove configuration profiles
permits an enterprise MDM server to be able to update these profiles remotely.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28850" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_provisioning_profiles">
<title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Provisioning Profiles</title>          
<description> In the <b>Add / Remove</b> section, set <b>Provisioning
Profiles</b> to Checked. </description> 
<rationale> Allowing an enterprise to add or remove provisioning profiles
permits an enterprise MDM server to be able to update these profiles remotely.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28851" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_apps">
<title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Apps</title>
<description> In the <b>Add / Remove</b> section, set <b>Apps</b>
to Checked.  This applies to managed apps, which are purchased by
the enterprise via the Volume Purchasing Program.
</description>
<rationale> Allowing an enterprise to add or remove managed apps provides the
enterprise with the ability to easily deploy enterprise applications to
devices. The MDM server can also specify that the data in managed apps be
removed when the MDM profile is removed, to protect enterprise data.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28852" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_addition_removal_of_settings">
<title>Allow Remote Addition/Removal of Settings</title>
<description> In the <b>Add / Remove</b> section, set <b>Settings</b> to Checked.
</description>
<rationale>Allowing an enterprise to add or remove settings
provides agility with regard to individual settings management.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28853" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_or_disallow_remote_change_of_device_password"> 
<title>Allow or Disallow Remote Change of Device Password</title>          
<description> In the <b>Security</b> section, set <b>Change device password</b>
to Unchecked or Checked. This entails a risk decision, though Checked is likely
to be appropriate for most scenarios. </description>
<rationale> Most enterprises are likely well-served by permitting the MDM
administrator to remotely send a change password command, in order to allow
users with forgotten passcodes to maintain access to their devices. This would
also permit an enterprise with appropriate authority, and which needed to
overcome the Data Protection feature (such as for forensics purposes) the
ability to do so.
<br />
<br />
At the same time, an attacker who has compromised communications between the
device and its MDM server (or the MDM server itself), could maliciously send a
password-change command to defeat the data-at-rest protection on the devices.
This would depend upon an attacker’s physical compromise of the device as well
as compromise of TLS communications (or the MDM server itself).
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28854" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="allow_remote_wipe"> 
<title>Allow Remote Wipe</title>          
<description> Set <b>Remote wipe</b> to Checked. </description> 
<rationale>Permitting remote wipe allows the enterprise to remotely wipe an iOS
device in the event that it is lost or stolen.
<br />
<br />
Note also that a layered configuration profile approach which involves specific
configuration profiles permitting access to specific services (which can be
removed by an MDM server), effectively permits selective removal of access to
services (and their local data). This can provide a form of remote wipe that is
more appropriate with BYOD scenarios that are incompatible with IT staff wiping
entire devices.
</rationale>
<ident cce="28855" />
</Rule>
</Group>
</Group>
