<Group id="passcode"> 
<title>Passcode</title> 
<description> The remarkable attention paid to passcode quality requirements
represents misplaced priorities in the current network environment, as
passcodes do not protect against many contemporary threats. However, setting a
passcode enables cryptographic features that can protect data on the device if
it is lost, stolen or temporarily out of possession. Hardware and software
cryptographic features of iOS devices – not present on typical desktop or
server systems – provide significant protections against the password-guessing
threat when the passcode feature is enabled. Furthermore, iOS devices are
likely to store only a single user’s credentials, while complex passcode
policies are designed to protect against the compromise of large numbers of
credentials when they are stored on a single system that becomes compromised
(such as a directory server). Onerous passcode policies may also drive users to
attempt to subvert the settings. For these reasons, IT decision makers should
understand that onerous passcode policies on iOS devices provide little value
(in the best case), and may end up being counterproductive.

The following publicly-available research provides rationale for these recommendations:
<ul>
<li><i>Apple iOS 4 Security Evaluation</i> by Dino Dai Zovi at: 
<b>http://www.trailofbits.com/resources/ios4_security_evaluation_slides.pdf</b>. The slides’ section “Attacking Passcode” provides highly relevant platform-specific discussion for iOS devices.
</li>
<li>NIST Special Publication 800-118 <i>DRAFT Guide to Enterprise Password
Management</i> at
<b>http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/PubsDrafts.html#SP-800-118</b> provides
discussion about factors that should be considered in order to create effective
password strength recommendations.
</li>
</ul>
</description>
 
<Group id="enable_passcode"> 
<title>Enable Passcode</title>
<description> The following passcode settings are recommended, and can be
deployed via a configuration profile. </description>

<Rule id="disable_simple_value_for_passcode"> 
<title>Disable Simple Value for Passcode</title>
<description> Set <b>Allow simple value</b> to <b>Unchecked</b>. </description>
<rationale>Disabling the use of simple values for a passcode enables display
of the entire keyboard for passcode entry, instead of only a numeric keypad.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28800" />
<ref nist="IA-5(1)"/>
</Rule> 

<Rule id="require_alphanumeric_value_for_passcode"> 
<title>Require Alphanumeric Value for Passcode</title> 
<description> Set <b>Require alphanumeric value</b> to <b>Checked</b>. </description> 
<rationale> Requiring alphanumeric values should increase the search space in a
password-guessing attack. </rationale> 
<ident cce="28801" />
<ref nist="IA-5(1)"/>
</Rule> 

<Rule id="set_minimum_passcode_length"> 
<title>Set Minimum Passcode Length</title> 
<description> Set <b>Minimum passcode length</b> to a value. </description>
<rationale> Setting a minimum length should increase the search space in a
password-guessing attack. A passcode length between 4 and 6 may be a reasonable balance
between user experience and security for many deployment scenarios.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28802" />
<ref nist="IA-5(1)" />
<ref disa="205" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="set_minimum_number_of_complex_characters"> 
<title>Set Minimum Number of Complex Characters</title> 
<description> Set <b>Minimum number of complex characters</b> to a value.
</description>
<rationale> Requiring complex characters should increase the search space in a
password-guessing attack. </rationale> 
<ident cce="28803" />
<ref nist="IA-5(1)"/>
</Rule> 

<Rule id="set_maximum_passcode_age"> 
<title>Set Maximum Passcode Age</title>
<description> Set <b>Maximum passcode age</b> to a number of a days, if there is a need for such rotation. </description>
<rationale> Changing passcodes prevents an attacker who has compromised the password from re-using it to regain access. This is an unlikely
scenario, but is addressed by setting a password expiration. A value of 120 days is likely to be adequate for many deployment scenarios.</rationale> 
<ident cce="28804" />
<ref nist="IA-5(1)" />
<ref disa="199" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="set_auto_lock_time"> 
<title>Set Auto-Lock Time</title> 
<description> Set <b>Auto-Lock (in minutes)</b> to a number of minutes.
A value of 5 minutes may be a reasonable balance
between user experience and security for many deployment scenarios.
</description> 
<rationale>Automatically locking the device after a period of inactivity
ensures that the device will require passcode entry if lost or left unattended. 
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28805" />
<ref disa="57" />
</Rule> 

<Rule id="set_passcode_history"> 
<title>Set Passcode History</title>
<description> Set <b>Passcode History</b> to <b>3</b>. </description>
<rationale>Setting a passcode history ensures that users cannot trivially
alternate between passcodes.</rationale> 
<ident cce="28806" />
<ref nist="IA-5(1)" />
<ref disa="200" />
</Rule>

<Rule id="set_grace_period_for_device_lock"> 
<title>Set Grace Period for Device Lock</title>
<description> Set <b>Grace period for device lock</b> to 5 minutes, or less.
</description>
<rationale> This permits unlock of the device after a certain period of time
has passed since the last device lock. Allowing a Grace Period enhances
usability and makes users more likely to tolerate passcode requirements.
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28807" />
<ref nist="IA-11"/>
</Rule> 

<Rule id="set_maximum_number_of_failed_attempts"> 
<title>Set Maximum Number of Failed Attempts</title>
<description> Set <b>Maximum number of failed attempts</b> to 10 attempts, or
fewer. </description>
<rationale> Setting the device to automatically erase after a number of failed
attempts can protect against witless password guessing attacks conducted
through the unlock screen. 
</rationale> 
<ident cce="28808" />
<ref nist="IA-5(1)" />
<ref disa="1383" />
</Rule>

</Group>

<Group id="understand_which_files_are_protected_by_encryption">
<title>Understand Which Files are Protected by Encryption</title>
<description> Enabling a passcode activates the Data Protection feature of iOS.
The Data Protection feature encrypts items with a key whose availability
depends on entry of the passcode. Currently, the following items are protected:
<ul>
<li> <b>Email messages</b> stored by the built-in Mail app </li> 
<li> <b>Inactive Apps’ Screenshots</b> displayed at app re-launch to create
impression of “instant resume” </li> 
<li> <b>Some Keychain Items</b> such as email passwords and iTunes backup password </li>
<li> <b>Data stored by third-party apps</b> which use the Data Protection API </li>
</ul>
</description>
<rationale> In fact, the rest of the files on the device are encrypted, but
they are still available to an attacker who can get privileged code to execute
on the device. This is because the encryption key for these files is available
even without the passcode (unlike the files above).

This was possible for a time using publicly-available tools which provide the ability
to execute privileged code on any device in physical possession. Examples of
these tools include jailbreak software such as <i>evasi0n</i> from the evad3rs
and <i>redsn0w</i> from The iPhone Dev Team. These applications leverage a
collection of exploits and other jailbreak utilities including <i>limera1n</i>
by George Hotz (geohot).

Note also that even if privileged code can be run by an attacker on a lost or
stolen iPhone, a password-guessing attack against the protected files must be
executed on the device itself. This is because the key which encrypts the items
listed above is derived from the passcode as well as a key that is bound to the
hardware of the device (and not considered extricable from it).

The following references provide detailed explanation:
<ul>
<li><i>iPhone data protection in depth</i> by Jean-Baptiste Bédrune and Jean Sigwald
(Sogeti ESEC) available at <b>http://esec-lab.sogeti.com/dotclear/public/publications/11-hitbamsterdam-iphonedataprotection.pdf</b> linked from <b>http://esec-lab.sogeti.com/post/iOS-5-data-protection-updates</b>.
</li>
<li><i>Apple iOS 4 Security Evaluation</i> by Dino Dai Zovi (Trail of Bits)
available at <b>http://trailofbits.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/apple-ios-4-security-evaluation-whitepaper.pdf</b> linked from <b>http://trailofbits.wordpress.com/2011/08/10/ios-4-security-evaluation/</b>.
</li>
</ul>
</rationale>           
</Group>
</Group>
