<Group id="restrictions"> 
<title>Restrictions</title>
<description> Some security-relevant restrictions can be placed upon the user
of the iOS device. </description> 

<Group id="device_functionality">
<title>Device Functionality</title>

<Rule id="disable_installation_of_third_party_apps"> 
<title>Disable Installation of Third-Party Apps</title>
<description> Unless necessary, disable <b>Allow installing apps</b>. This is
unusual for a general-purpose device. </description>
<rationale> While iOS includes features such as sandboxing that are designed to
prevent third-party apps from influencing the integrity of the operating
system, they do have the ability to access data stored on the device such as
Address Book, Location Data, or the Photo Library, and have the
ability to transmit this information. </rationale> 
<ref nist="CM-11(2)"/>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_camera"> 
<title>Disable Camera</title>       
<description> Disable <b>Allow use of camera</b>, if concerns exist about
capturing sensitive images. </description> 
<ref nist="SC-42"/>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_screen_capture">
<title>Disable Screen Capture</title>
<description> Disable <b>Allow screen capture</b>, if concerns exist about
storing screen contents in the Photo Library. </description>
<rationale> While unlikely, this feature could accidentally be triggered (by
simultaneously pressing the Home and Sleep buttons) and lead to storage of
sensitive information outside the intended storage area.</rationale>
</Rule>
</Group>

<Group id="applications">
<title>Applications</title>

<Rule id="disable_itunes_store">
<title>Disable use of iTunes Store</title> 
<description> Deselect <b>Allow use of iTunes Store</b>, to prevent access to media content and applications.</description>
<rationale>iTunes provides access to media content and applications.</rationale>
</Rule>

<Group id="safari">
<title>Safari</title>
<description>The Safari web browser is included with iOS, and the following
section provides discussion of security-relevant settings.
Additional information about Safari security settings on
iOS is available at <b>http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1677</b>.
</description>

<Rule id="disable_safari">
<title>Disable Safari</title>
<description>If Safari can be disabled, uncheck <b>Allow use of Safari</b>.
<b><i>This is very unusual for a general-purpose device.</i></b></description>
<rationale>Devices in specialized use cases may not require the use of a web
browser such as Safari.
</rationale> 
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_safari_autofill">
<title>Disable Safari Autofill</title>
<description> Deselect <b>Enable autofill</b>, to prevent storage of
some potentially sensitive information by Safari. </description>
<rationale>Storage of autofill information permits an attacker to harvest
previously-used credentials in the event that the device becomes
compromised.
</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="enable_safari_fraud_warning">
<title>Enable Safari Fraud Warning</title>
<description> Select <b>Force fraud warning</b>, to ensure users are
warned when visiting known-fraudulent web sites. </description>
<rationale>Fraudulent web sites may try to collect sensitive information
from users.
</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_javascript">
<title>Disable JavaScript</title>
<description> Deselect <b>Enable javascript</b>, to prevent JavaScript from
running in Safari. <i>This makes the Internet virtually useless and is only
appropriate for unusual, high-security scenarios.</i>
</description>
<rationale>JavaScript permits client-side scripts to run within the browser.
Nearly all modern web sites use JavaScript, though its functionality
constitutes an attack surface.</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="enable_safari_pop_up_blocking">
<title>Enable Safari Pop-up Blocking</title>
<description> Set <b>Block pop-ups</b> to <b>Checked</b>. </description>
<rationale>Blocking pop-ups prevents malicious or obnoxious web sites from
interfering with the user in an unexpected and possibly security-relevant
manner.</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="accept_cookies_from_visited_sites_only">
<title>Accept Cookies from Visited Sites Only</title>
<description> Set <b>Accept cookies</b> to <b>From visited sites</b>.</description>
<rationale>Accepting cookies from only visited sites decreases the extent
to which third-party web sites can track user activity.</rationale>
</Rule>
</Group>
</Group>

<Group id="icloud_configuration">
<title>iCloud configuration</title>
<description>Policies regarding the usage of cloud-based storage services
continue to evolve, as do the assurances of safety by cloud providers. In
general, if there is a need to store potentially sensitive information on the
iOS device, then the following restrictions should be considered.</description>

<Rule id="disable_icloud_backups">
<title>Disable iCloud Backups</title>
<description>Set <b>Allow backup</b> to <b>Unchecked</b>. </description>
<rationale>Backing up iOS devices to iCloud may involve placing enterprise data
on systems that are not controlled by the enterprise.</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_icloud_document_sync">
<title>Disable iCloud Document Sync</title>
<description>Set <b>Allow document sync</b> to <b>Unchecked</b>.</description>
<rationale>Synchronizing documents to iCloud involves placing data on systems
that are not controlled by the enterprise.
</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_icloud_photo_stream">
<title>Disable iCloud Photo Stream</title>
<description>Set <b>Allow Photo Stream</b> to <b>Unchecked</b>.</description>
<rationale>If photographs may constitute sensitive enterprise data, then
transferring photos to iCloud could involve placing such data on systems that
are not controlled by the enterprise.</rationale>
</Rule>
</Group>

<Group id="security_and_privacy">
<title>Security and Privacy</title>

<Rule id="disable_sending_diagnostic_data_to_apple">
<title>Disable Sending Diagnostic Data to Apple</title>
<description> Disable <b>Allow diagnositic data to be sent to Apple</b> to
Unchecked, if this presents concerns about inadvertent transmission of
sensitive data.</description>
<rationale>Diagnostic data could be considered sensitive in some environments
and not transmitted outside enterprise control.
</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="disable_user_acceptance_of_untrusted_tls_certificates">
<title>Disable User Acceptance of Untrusted TLS Certificates</title>
<description> Set <b>Allow user to accept untrusted TLS certificates</b> to
Unchecked.  Root CAs trusted by iOS are available at
<b>http://support.apple.com/kb/HT5012</b>.
</description>
<rationale>Presentation of an untrusted TLS certificate to client software
could indicate a man-in-the-middle attack.  
</rationale>
</Rule>

<Rule id="force_encrypted_backups">
<title>Force Encrypted Backups</title>
<description> Set <b>Force encrypted backups</b> to Checked, in order
to ensure that the contents of iOS devices are encrypted when backed up
onto host computers.
</description>
<rationale>Encrypting device backups protects hosts backups even if the host
later becomes compromised.  </rationale>
</Rule>
</Group>
</Group>
