<Group id="device_usage_and_handling"> 
<title>Device Usage and Handling</title>  
<description> This chapter provides recommendations on device usage and
handling, for both administrators and users. Section  provides handling and
usage guidance for administrators. These topics include issuing devices,
managing and accounting for devices once in users’ hands, and effectively
educating users on secure device usage.  Further, there are important
recommendations such as maintaining physical control of the device, not
jailbreaking the device, and preventing connections to untrusted networks. This
section closes with suggested usage statements that could be provided to users.
</description>


<Group id="handling_guidance_for_administrators"> 
<title>Handling Guidance for Administrators</title>  
<description> If the enterprise is planning to procure and distribute devices
to users, administrators should establish procedures for this activity. Some
items from this section may not apply to BYOD scenarios, however, such as
inventory management and prompt retirement of unsupported devices.
</description>
            
<Group id="establish_a_user_training_program"> 
<title>Establish a User Training Program</title>           
<description> Create or make available training resources to educate users
about device security issues and organization policies. Ensure that all device
users are aware of risks and properly trained to mitigate them. </description>
<rationale> Security and policy awareness training reduces the risk of
user-originated security compromise. This relates closely to any agreements
between the user and enterprise regarding device handling, which should be
verified for each user prior to their being issued a device, as described in
Section . </rationale>  
</Group>

<Group id="issuing_devices"> 
<title>Issuing Devices</title>  
<description> This section provides recommendations for enterprises issuing iOS
devices. </description>
 
<Group id="issue_only_supported_devices"> 
<title>Issue Only Supported Devices</title>           
<description> Ensure that only supported hardware versions are issued.
Supported hardware versions are defined as those that can run the latest
version of iOS and receive all updates. To determine this, administrators will
need to manually note which systems can be updated whenever security updates
are provided. </description> 
<rationale> Sometimes only the current version and the previous version of the
iPhone or iPad hardware can run all updates. This suggests that IT planners
should anticipate a 2 year (or 3 year, at most) refresh cycle for
enterprise-purchased devices. </rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="erase_and_reset_devices_if_re_issuing"> 
<title>Erase and Reset Devices, if Re-issuing</title>           
<description> If re-issuing devices, erase them before distributing them to
users. </description> 
<rationale> Use the command <b>Settings &gt; General &gt; Reset &gt; Erase All
Content and Settings</b> to erase a device. Clearing content and settings
returns the device to a stable state and prevents accidental exposure of the
prior user’s data. </rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="update_device_to_user_registration"> 
<title>Update Device-to-User Registration</title>           
<description> Establish a system for attributing individual devices to users
prior to issuance. This information must be updated every time a device is
issued or transferred. Existing inventory tracking systems or MDM software can
enable automation of this process. The following pieces of information from
each device can be useful: <ul> <li>UDID (Unique Device Identifier) </li>
<li>Serial Number </li> <li>IMEI (if equipped with a cellular connectivity)
</li> <li>Model Number </li> <li>Wi-Fi MAC Address </li> <li>Bluetooth MAC
Address </li></ul>MDM products may also report this information. This
information should be protected accordingly. </description>
</Group>

<Group id="verify_user_training_history"> 
<title>Verify User Training History</title>           
<description> Ensure that users are familiar with the training before receiving
a new device, and at regular intervals afterward. </description>
</Group>

<Group id="provide_recharging_hardware_with_device"> 
<title>Provide Recharging Hardware with Device</title>           
<description> Distribute AC power adapters to users when issuing devices and
warn users not to connect their devices to unauthorized systems. It may be
prudent to distribute additional AC power adapters to remove the temptation to
connect the devices to unknown PCs. </description> 
<rationale> Connecting iOS devices to unauthorized systems, even if only
intending to recharge the device, presents a security risk. Providing a power
adapter, and easy access to replacements and additional adapters, will help
combat temptation to connect to other systems. Users should never be left with
connecting to a computer as their only option to recharge their device.
</rationale>  
</Group>
</Group>

<Group id="dealing_with_a_lost_or_stolen_ios_device"> 
<title>Dealing with a Lost or Stolen iOS Device</title>  
<description> If an iOS device is reported as lost or stolen, the device should
be immediately disabled to prevent unauthorized use or access. The system
administrator can issue a remote “Wipe” command to erase all media, data and
settings from the device, restoring it to factory settings. Be aware of the
circumstances under which issuing a wipe may not be possible, such as keeping a
device in Airplane Mode or simply lacking network connectivity. </description>
 
<Group id="establish_procedure_for_lost_or_stolen_ios_devices">
<title>Establish Procedure for Lost or Stolen iOS devices</title>           
<description> Establish and test a procedure to issue a wipe command to erase
data from a lost or stolen iOS device. Ensure that users are also aware of
their responsibilities to report lost or stolen devices. Wipe commands can 
be issued by an MDM server or by Exchange ActiveSync. Users can also initiate 
remote wipe using iCloud, if the device is enrolled. </description>
</Group>

</Group>

<Group id="retire_devices_which_cannot_run_latest_os_version"> 
<title>Retire Devices Which Cannot Run Latest OS Version</title>           
<description> Immediately retire any devices which cannot run the latest iOS
version. This requires vigilance on the part of administrators, to monitor when
an update is issued but is not supported on older devices. </description>
<rationale> iOS updates include both security patches as well as new
functionality. Ensure that all iOS device hardware provided and managed by the
enterprise can always run the latest iOS. For example, all iPhone 3G devices
should be immediately retired, because they cannot run iOS 7. </rationale>
</Group>

<Group id="monitor_devices_using_mdm_especially_for_updates"> 
<title>Monitor Devices Using MDM, Especially for Updates</title>           
<description> MDM products enable enterprise integration and reporting for 
iOS devices. Regularly monitor the status of devices using MDM software and 
respond accordingly. Particularly important is
ensuring that the version of iOS is kept up to date, which implies that all
available security updates are installed. Some MDM products include the ability
to disable access to enterprise resources if devices are not kept up to date or
are otherwise not compliant. </description>
</Group>

</Group>

<Group id="handling_guidance_for_users"> 
<title>Handling Guidance for Users</title>  
<description> User education is one of the strongest tools an organization can
use to minimize the risk of security issues. Educating users helps raise
awareness of their actions and helps them understand the reasoning behind
policy decisions. This section details physical handling guidance and security
policy topics to be reinforced to users through an organization-developed user
education program. </description>
 
<Group id="physical_control"> 
<title>Physical Control</title>  
<description> Maintain physical control of your iOS device at all times.
</description> 
<rationale> All guidance contained in this document depends upon uninterrupted
physical control of your iOS device. It is your responsibility to maintain
possession of the device. Never leave your iOS device unattended in an insecure
location. An unattended device is at high risk for loss, theft, and other forms
of compromise that could violate the confidentiality, integrity, or
availability of the device and the information contained therein. </rationale>

<Group id="surrendering_physical_control"> 
<title>Surrendering Physical Control</title>  
<description> Learn the proper procedure for relinquishing control of the iOS
device to another entity. </description> 
<rationale> There are times when physical control of the iOS device must be
surrendered, such as when passing through security or customs inspections. The
following are possible methods of mitigating potential loss of personal,
financial or company information. <ul> <li>Before entering security or customs
checkpoints, power down the iOS device, remove its SIM card using the SIM eject
tool or an unwound paper clip, and place the SIM card in a physically separate
location such as a bag or your coat pocket. </li> <li>Place the device in a
clear, tamper evident bag. </li> <li>Ensure passcode is enabled.
</li></ul>Organizations may elect to require all of these steps based on their
security policy. </rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="notify_security_or_administrative_personnel_upon_loss_of_physical_control">
<title>Notify Security or Administrative Personnel Upon Loss of Physical
Control</title>  
<description> Obtain the contact information of your System Security Officer
(SSO) for use in reporting the loss of physical control of your iOS device and
learn which scenarios require SSO notification. If there is any suspicion that
a device has been accessed by an unauthorized user, report the incident
immediately to the appropriate SSO or administrative personnel. </description>
<rationale> If a device is lost or stolen, the administrator or SSO should be
contacted immediately in order to execute the remote wipe procedure through
Microsoft Exchange, and to create a detailed incident
report describing the event. Even if you lose control of your iOS device for a
period of time but regain it later, it should be inspected for signs of
physical compromise by system administration or security personnel. If a
compromise is suspected, actions should be taken to sanitize or destroy the
device, depending on the sensitivity of the data and severity of the situation
in which it was compromised. </rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="be_aware_of_your_surroundings"> 
<title>Be Aware of Your Surroundings</title>  
<description> Be aware of the danger of “shoulder surfing,” which refers to the
ability of others to see your entry or viewing of sensitive information on the
phone. </description> 
<rationale> Because anyone nearby can potentially view any information
displayed on the device, be wary of your environment when viewing any sensitive
information, and particularly wary when entering passwords. Due to obvious
physical and user interface constraints, password entry is susceptible to
shoulder surfing, whether by observation of finger position or brief display of
each character on-screen. Some third-party products may be available to
mitigate this risk. </rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="follow_procedures_for_secure_areas"> 
<title>Follow Procedures for Secure Areas</title>  
<description> Learn the proper procedure for handling your iOS device in a
secure area. </description> 
<rationale> If your organization has a secure area for talking about
confidential information, you should be educated about the risks of bringing
your iOS device into those areas. The following policies may be implemented for
device security in secure areas: <ul> <li>Leave iOS devices outside conference
rooms. </li> <li>Applications that record audio or video must be removed or
their use restricted. </li> <li>Ensure the camera on the back of the iOS device
is blocked (e.g. opaque tape) to prevent photo or video recording. </li>
<li>Ensure that all iOS devices, if present, are in airplane mode with Wi-Fi
turned off. </li></ul> </rationale>
</Group>

</Group>

<Group id="do_not_jailbreak_or_unlock_your_ios_device"> 
<title>Do Not Jailbreak or Unlock Your iOS Device</title>  
<description> Jailbreaking is a term that describes the process of modifying
the iOS device’s operating system, often with the goal of running unsigned code
or performing unsupported customizations to the operating system. Unlocking
allows users to operate an iOS device on a cellular network it is not
authorized to connect to. Unlocking an iOS device requires a jailbroken iOS
device first. </description>
<warning> <b>Do not jailbreak or unlock your iOS device.</b> Doing so makes it
much easier for attackers to introduce malicious code onto the device.
</warning> 
<rationale>Jailbreaking significantly increases the iOS device’s
susceptibility to compromise. It disables the enforcement of code signatures, a
critical security feature. This enables access to a wide range of software with
little accountability and minimal vetting. Jailbreaking tools also typically
install and activates services that make the device easier to remotely access,
such as SSH. </rationale>  
</Group>

<Group id="install_software_updates_when_available"> 
<title>Install Software Updates When Available</title>  
<description> Install software updates as quickly as possible. Updates can be
applied over-the-air (OTA) or by using iTunes. Available updates are indicated by a red circle on the "Settings" app. Information about available updates can be found by selecting <b>Settings &gt; General &gt; Software Update</b>.
</description> 
<rationale> Software updates for iOS devices can contain fixes for security
vulnerabilities. As these vulnerabilities often become public knowledge when
the updates are released, installing updates as soon as they are available is
strongly recommended. Supported 3rd party software should not be broken by
updates.
</rationale>  
</Group>

<Group id="connect_only_to_trusted_networks"> 
<title>Connect Only to Trusted Networks</title>  
<description> Do not connect your iOS device to untrusted wireless networks.
</description> 
<rationale> Connections to untrusted WiFi networks introduce some risks.
Attacks on the iOS device, or eavesdropping on the data it transmits, can occur
due to use of such networks. Because the user controls the WiFi settings, he or
she must understand the risks associated with untrusted wireless networks and
behave responsibly. Some organizations have policies that forbid connection to
non-enterprise controlled networks. Other organizations forbid or prevent the
use of personal devices on enterprise networks. </rationale>  
</Group>

<Group id="email_accounts"> 
<title>Email Accounts</title>
  
<Group id="consider_risks_of_using_personal_email_accounts"> 
<title>Consider Risks of Using Personal Email Accounts</title>  
<description> Do not add personal email accounts to your iOS device, unless you
are comfortable with (or approved for) the additional risk. </description> 
<rationale> Adding personal email accounts implies that personal, non-company
data will be transferred to and stored on the device. This likely violates
organizational policy with regard to use of company resources for personal use,
but it also increases risk. It increases the risk of your personal information
being compromised as a result of an attack against the device, and also
increases the risks of company information being compromised as a result of an
attack carried out against your personal email account. See the next section
for more information about phishing attacks and the motivation for segregating
email accounts between different systems. </rationale> 
</Group>

<Group id="be_aware_of_phishing"> 
<title>Be Aware of Phishing</title>  
<description> Be aware of phishing attempts, including receiving mobile
profiles from attackers. </description>
<rationale> Phishing is a term referring to a fraudulent communication (usually
email) pretending to be from a reputable source asking for personal, financial
or company information. Adding personal email accounts to your iOS device
greatly increases your availability to receive phishing emails, which may
accidentally release important information about yourself or your organization.
By removing personal email accounts from the device, you are protecting your
organization from divulging information through your device to these malicious
actors. </rationale>  
</Group>

</Group>

<Group id="disable_bluetooth_if_practical"> 
<title>Disable Bluetooth if Practical</title>  
<description> Disable Bluetooth communication if not necessary. </description> 
<rationale> Disabling Bluetooth reduces the possible attack surface for
exploitation, although such vulnerabilities are rare and the iOS over-the-air
update process enables rapid patching upon any public disclosure. Bluetooth
also permits wireless device discovery and can be used to reveal a limited
amount of information from the device. If practical, it is safest to keep
Bluetooth disabled. The Bluetooth profiles available on iOS devices are
documented at <b>http://support.apple.com/kb/HT3647</b>.
</rationale>  
</Group>

<Group id="recharge_device_only_through_approved_methods"> 
<title>Recharge Device Only Through Approved Methods</title>  
<description> Recharge your device by either connecting to an
organization-approved system or by using the AC power adapter you received when
you were issued your device. </description> 
<rationale> Connecting your iOS device to unknown systems exposes the device to
unnecessary risks, including the loss of personal or company information.
Syncing only with trusted systems also helps maintain the integrity of your iOS
device. </rationale>  
</Group>

<Group id="do_not_use_unapproved_peripherals_on_your_ios_device"> 
<title>Do Not Use Unapproved Peripherals on Your iOS Device</title>  
<description> Many different types of iOS device accessories are available for
use by consumers. Some of these devices allow access to a keyboard, magnetic
card reader, or USB flash drive reader.
Users should only use accessories approved for use by the enterprise.
</description> 
<rationale> Due to the physical access nature of these accessories, security
risks may be present when attached to an iOS device. 
</rationale>        
</Group>
</Group>
</Group>
