<Benchmark xmlns="http://checklists.nist.gov/xccdf/1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" id="MacOSX10.11">
<status date="2015-10-09">draft</status>
  <title>DoD Consensus Settings for Mac OS X 10.11</title>
  <description>These security settings for Mac OS X 10.11
  were developed by the DoD Joint Consensus Working Group.
  </description>
  <!-- Many of the XCCDF elements used here 
       are not used in the manner originally intended by
       the XCCDF specification; 
       this is a result of the SRG-based process,
       which mixes requirements about security functionality
       with requirements for security configuration. -->
<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000060" srgid="SRG-OS-000031" nist="AOSX-10-000005" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Set a Default Screensaver for All Users</title>
<description>A default screensaver must be configured for all users, as the screensaver will act as a session time-out lock for the system and must be one that conceals the contents of the screen from unauthorized users. The screensaver must not display any sensitive information or reveal the contents of the locked session screen. Publicly viewable images can include static or dynamic images such as patterns used with screen savers, photographic images, solid colors, a clock, a battery life indicator, or a blank screen.</description>
<check>To view the currently selected screen saver for the logged in user, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep moduleName<p/><p/>If there is no result or defined moduleName, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Login Window Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000057" srgid="SRG-OS-000029" nist="AOSX-10-000010" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Set a Screensaver Timeout of 15 Minutes or Less</title>
<description>A screensaver must be enabled and set to require a password to unlock. The timeout should be set to fifteen minutes of inactivity. This mitigates the risk that a user might forget to manually lock the screen before stepping away from the computer.<p/><p/>A session time-out lock is a temporary action taken when a user stops work and moves away from the immediate physical vicinity of the information system, but does not log out because of the temporary nature of the absence. Rather than relying on the user to manually lock their operating system session prior to vacating the vicinity, operating systems need to be able to identify when a user's session has idled and take action to initiate the session lock.</description>
<check>To check if the system has a configuration profile configured to enable the screen saver after a time-out period, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep idleTime<p/><p/>The check should return a value of '900' or less for idleTime. If not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Login Window Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000056" srgid="SRG-OS-000028" nist="AOSX-10-000020" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Require a Password to Unlock the Screensaver</title>
<description>Users must be prompted to enter their passwords when unlocking the screensaver. The screensaver acts as a session lock and prevents unauthorized users from accessing the current user's account.</description>
<check>To check if the system will prompt users to enter their passwords to unlock the screensaver, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep askForPassword<p/><p/>If there is no result, or if askForPassword is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Login Window Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000067" srgid="SRG-OS-000032" nist="AOSX-10-000030" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Login Events</title>
<description>Remote access services, such as those providing remote access to network devices and information systems, increase risk and expose those systems to possible cyber attacks, so all remote access should be closely monitored and audited. Only authorized users should be permitted to remotely access DoD non-public information systems. An attacker might attempt to log in as an authorized user, through stolen credentials, unpatched exploits of the remote access service, or brute force attempts to guess a valid username and password. If a user is attempting to log in to a system from an unusual location or at an unusual time, or if there are many failed attempts, there is a possibility that the system is the target of a cyber attack. Auditing logon events mitigates this risk by recording all logon attempts, successful and unsuccessful, to the system.</description>
<check>To check to make sure the audit daemon is configured to log all login events, both local and remote, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>The flag 'lo' should be included in the list of flags set. If it is not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,lo/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-000068" srgid="SRG-OS-000033" nist="AOSX-10-000035" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the rexec Service</title>
<description>The 'rexec' service must be disabled. The 'rexec' service does not implement crypto and has had several security vulnerabilities in the past. It is disabled by default; enabling it would increase the attack surface of the system.<p/><p/>Without confidentiality protection mechanisms, unauthorized individuals may gain access to sensitive information via a remote access session. <p/><p/>Remote access is access to DoD non-public information systems by an authorized user (or an information system) communicating through an external, non-organization-controlled network. Remote access methods include, for example, dial-up, broadband, and wireless. <p/> <p/>Encryption provides a means to secure the remote connection to prevent unauthorized access to the data traversing the remote access connection (e.g., RDP) thereby providing a degree of confidentiality. The encryption strength of mechanism is selected based on the security categorization of the information.</description>
<check>To check if the 'rexec' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.rexecd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.rexecd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'rexec' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.rexecd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-001453" srgid="SRG-OS-000250" nist="AOSX-10-000040" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Telnet service</title>
<description>The telnet service must be disabled, as it sends all data, including the user's password, in a clear text form that can be easily intercepted and read. Passwords need to be protected at all times and encryption is the standard method for protecting passwords. If passwords are not encrypted, they can be plainly read (i.e., clear text) and easily compromised. Disabling telnet is one way to mitigate this risk. Authorized users should be instructed to use an alternate service that implements cryptography for remote access sessions, such as SSH.</description>
<check>To check if the 'telnet' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.telnetd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'rexec' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000050" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the rshd Service</title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The 'rshd' service must be disabled.</description>
<check>To check if the 'rshd' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.rshd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.rshd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'rshd' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.rshd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000055" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Screen Sharing</title>
<description>The Screen Sharing feature allows remote users to view or control the desktop of the current user. A malicious user can take advantage of Screen Sharing to gain full access to the system remotely, either with stolen credentials or by guessing the username and password. Disabling Screen Sharing mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if the 'screen sharing' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.screensharing<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.screensharing" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'screen sharing' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.screensharing<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000065" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Bluetooth Devices</title>
<description>The Bluetooth kernel extension must be disabled, as wireless access introduces unnecessary security risks. Disabling Bluetooth support with a configuration profile mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>If Bluetooth connectivity is required to facilitate use of approved external devices, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if Bluetooth is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep DisableBluetooth<p/><p/>If there is no result, or if DisableBluetooth is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Bluetooth Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000070" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Wi-Fi Network Device</title>
<description>Use of Wi-Fi to connect to unauthorized networks may facilitate the exfiltration of mission data.</description>
<check>If the system requires Wi-Fi to connect to an authorized network, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the Wi-Fi network device is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/networksetup -listallnetworkservices<p/><p/>A disabled device will have an asterisk in front of its name. If the Wi-Fi device is missing this asterisk, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the Wi-Fi network device, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/networksetup -setnetworkserviceenabled 'Wi-Fi' off</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000075" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Infrared Controller</title>
<description>Infrared [IR] kernel support must be disabled to prevent users from controlling the system with IR devices. By default, if IR is enabled, the system will accept IR control from any remote.</description>
<check>To check if IR support is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults read /Library/Preferences/com.apple.driver.AppleIRController DeviceEnabled<p/><p/>If the result is not '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable IR, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults write /Library/Preferences/com.apple.driver.AppleIRController DeviceEnabled -bool FALSE</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000085" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Blank CDs from Generating Prompts</title>
<description>Applications should not be configured to launch automatically when a disk is inserted. This potentially circumvents anti-virus software and allows malicious users to craft disks that can exploit user applications. Disabling Automatic Actions for blank CDs mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>If an approved HBSS DCM/DLP solution is installed, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the system has the correct setting for blank CDs in the configuration profile, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 'com.apple.digihub.blank.cd.appeared'<p/><p/>If this is not defined or 'action' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Custom Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000090" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Blank DVDs from Generating Prompts</title>
<description>Applications should not be configured to launch automatically when a disk is inserted. This potentially circumvents anti-virus software and allows malicious users to craft disks that can exploit user applications. Disabling Automatic Actions for blank DVDs mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>If an approved HBSS DCM/DLP solution is installed, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the system has the correct setting for blank DVDs in the configuration profile, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 'com.apple.digihub.blank.dvd.appeared'<p/><p/>If this is not defined or 'action' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Custom Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000095" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Music CDs from Generating Prompts</title>
<description>Applications should not be configured to launch automatically when a disk is inserted. This potentially circumvents anti-virus software and allows malicious users to craft disks that can exploit user applications. Disabling Automatic Actions for music CDs mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>If an approved HBSS DCM/DLP solution is installed, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the system has the correct setting for music CDs in the configuration profile, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 'com.apple.digihub.cd.music.appeared'<p/><p/>If this is not defined or 'action' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Custom Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000100" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Picture CDs from Generating Prompts</title>
<description>Applications should not be configured to launch automatically when a disk is inserted. This potentially circumvents anti-virus software and allows malicious users to craft disks that can exploit user applications. Disabling Automatic Actions for picture CDs mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>If an approved HBSS DCM/DLP solution is installed, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the system has the correct setting for picture CDs in the configuration profile, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 'com.apple.digihub.cd.picture.appeared'<p/><p/>If this is not defined or 'action' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Custom Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000105" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Video DVDs from Generating Prompts</title>
<description>Applications should not be configured to launch automatically when a disk is inserted. This potentially circumvents anti-virus software and allows malicious users to craft disks that can exploit user applications. Disabling Automatic Actions for video DVDs mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>If an approved HBSS DCM/DLP solution is installed, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the system has the correct setting for video DVDs in the configuration profile, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 'com.apple.digihub.dvd.video.appeared'<p/><p/>If this is not defined or 'action' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Custom Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000016" srgid="SRG-OS-000002" nist="AOSX-10-000110" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Remove or Disable Temporary User Accounts</title>
<description>If temporary user accounts remain active when no longer needed or for an excessive period, these accounts may be targeted by attackers to gain unauthorized access. To mitigate this risk, automated termination of all temporary accounts must be set upon account creation. <p/><p/>Temporary accounts are established as part of normal account activation procedures when there is a need for short-term accounts without the demand for immediacy in account activation. <p/><p/>If temporary accounts are used, the operating system must be configured to automatically terminate these types of accounts after a DoD-defined time period of 72 hours.<p/><p/>To address access requirements, many operating systems may be integrated with enterprise level authentication/access mechanisms that meet or exceed access control policy requirements.</description>
<check>Password policy can be set with the pwpolicy utility. The variable names may vary depending on how the policy was set. To check if the password policy is configured to disable a temporary account after 72 hours, run the following command to output the password policy to the screen, substituting the correct user name in place of username:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy -u username getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2<p/><p/>If there is no output, and password policy is not controlled by a directory server, this is a finding.<p/><p/>Otherwise, look for the line '&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;'.<p/><p/>In the array that follows, there should be a &lt;dict&gt; section that contains a check &lt;string&gt; that allows users to log in if 'policyAttributeCurrentTime' is less than the result of adding 'policyAttributeCreationTime' to 72hours (259299 seconds). The check might use a variable defined in its policyParameters section.<p/><p/>If the check does not exist or if the check adds too great an amount of time to 'policyAttributeCreationTime', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting may be enforced using a configuration profile or by a directory server.<p/><p/>To set the password policy without a configuration profile, run the following command to save a copy of the current policy file, substituting the correct user name in place of username:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy -u username getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the resulting password policy file in a text editor.<p/><p/>If other policy settings are present, and the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt; already exists, insert the following text after the &lt;array&gt; tag that immediately follows it:<p/><p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;policyAttributeCurrentTime &lt; policyAttributeCreationTime + 259299&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Disable Temporary Account&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>At a minimum, edit the file to ensure that it contains the following text:<p/><p/>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;<p/>&lt;!DOCTYPE plist PUBLIC "-//Apple//DTD PLIST 1.0//EN" "http://www.apple.com/DTDs/PropertyList-1.0.dtd"&gt;<p/>&lt;plist version="1.0"&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;array&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;policyAttributeCurrentTime &lt; policyAttributeCreationTime + 259299&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Disable Temporary Account&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/array&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/plist&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file, substituting the correct user name in place of username:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy -u username setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001682" srgid="SRG-OS-000123" nist="AOSX-10-000115" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Emergency Administrator Accounts from Expiring</title>
<description>Emergency administrator accounts are privileged accounts which are established in response to crisis situations where the need for rapid account activation is required. Therefore, emergency account activation may bypass normal account authorization processes. If these accounts are automatically disabled, system maintenance during emergencies may not be possible, thus adversely affecting system availability.<p/><p/>Emergency administrator accounts are different from infrequently used accounts (i.e., local logon accounts used by system administrators when network or normal logon/access is not available). Infrequently used accounts also remain available and are not subject to automatic termination dates. However, an emergency administrator account is normally a different account which is created for use by vendors or system maintainers.<p/><p/>To address access requirements, many operating systems can be integrated with enterprise-level authentication/access mechanisms that meet or exceed access control policy requirements.</description>
<check>If an emergency account has been created on the workstation, check the expiration settings of a local account using the following command, replacing username with the correct value:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy -u username getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2<p/><p/>If there is output, ensure that the account policies do not restrict the ability to log on after a certain date or amount of time. If they do, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To remove all pwpolicy settings for an emergency account, run the following command, replacing username with the correct value:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy -u username clearaccountpolicies<p/><p/>Otherwise, to change the password policy for an emergency account and only remove some policy sections, run the following command to save a copy of the current policy file for the specified username:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy -u username getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the resulting password policy file in a text editor and remove any policyContent sections that would restrict the ability to log on after a certain date or amount of time.<p/><p/>To remove the section cleanly, remove the entire text that begins with &lt;dict&gt;, contains the like &lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;'/key&gt;, and ends with &lt;/dict&gt;.<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy -u username setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000018" srgid="SRG-OS-000004" nist="AOSX-10-000120" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Account Creation</title>
<description>Once an attacker establishes initial access to a system, the attacker often attempts to create a persistent method of re-establishing access. One way to accomplish this is for the attacker to create a new account. Auditing of account creation mitigates this risk.<p/><p/>To address access requirements, many operating systems may be integrated with enterprise level authentication/access/auditing mechanisms that meet or exceed access control policy requirements.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>The account creation events are logged by way of the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001403" srgid="SRG-OS-000239" nist="AOSX-10-000125" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Account Modification</title>
<description>Once an attacker establishes initial access to a system, the attacker often attempts to create a persistent method of re-establishing access. One way to accomplish this is for the attacker to create a new account or modify an existing one. Auditing of account creation and modification is one method for mitigating this risk.<p/><p/>To address access requirements, many operating systems can be integrated with enterprise-level authentication/access/auditing mechanisms that meet or exceed access control policy requirements.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>The account creation events are logged by way of the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001404" srgid="SRG-OS-000240" nist="AOSX-10-000130" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Account Disablement</title>
<description>When operating system accounts are disabled, user accessibility is affected. The system must audit account disablement actions so that administrator users can detect and respond to such events. Such a capability greatly reduces the risk that operating system accessibility will be negatively affected for extended periods of time and provides logging that can be used for forensic purposes. <p/><p/>To address access requirements, many operating systems can be integrated with enterprise-level authentication/access/auditing mechanisms that meet or exceed access control policy requirements.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>The account modification events are logged by way of the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001405" srgid="SRG-OS-000241" nist="AOSX-10-000135" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Account Removal</title>
<description>When operating system accounts are removed, user accessibility is affected. The system must audit account removal actions so that administrator users can detect and respond to such events. Such a capability greatly reduces the risk that operating system accessibility will be negatively affected for extended periods of time and provides logging that can be used for forensic purposes. <p/><p/>To address access requirements, many operating systems can be integrated with enterprise-level authentication/access/auditing mechanisms that meet or exceed access control policy requirements.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>The account modification events are logged by way of the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000139" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the SMB File Sharing Service</title>
<description>File Sharing is usually non-essential and must be disabled if not required. Enabling any service increases the attack surface for an intruder. By disabling unnecessary services, the attack surface is minimized.</description>
<check>If SMB File Sharing is required, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the 'SMB File Sharing' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.smbd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.smbd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'SMB File Sharing' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.smbd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000140" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Apple File (AFP) Sharing Service</title>
<description>File Sharing is non-essential and must be disabled. Enabling any service increases the attack surface for an intruder. By disabling unnecessary services, the attack surface is minimized.</description>
<check>To check if the 'Apple File (AFP) Sharing' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.AppleFileServer<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.AppleFileServer" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'Apple File (AFP) Sharing' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.AppleFileServer<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000141" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the NFS Sharing Service</title>
<description>If the system does not require access to NFS (Network File System) file shares or is not acting as an NFS server, then support for NFS is non-essential and NFS services must be disabled. NFS is a network file system protocol supported by Unix-like operating systems. Enabling any service increases the attack surface for an intruder. By disabling unnecessary services, the attack surface is minimized.</description>
<check>If the NFS daemon is required, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the NFS daemon is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.nfsd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.nfsd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'NFS' daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.nfsd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000142" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the NFS Lock Daemon</title>
<description>If the system does not require access to NFS (Network File System) file shares or is not acting as an NFS server, then support for NFS is non-essential and NFS services must be disabled. NFS is a network file system protocol supported by Unix-like operating systems. Enabling any service increases the attack surface for an intruder. By disabling unnecessary services, the attack surface is minimized.</description>
<check>If the NFS lock daemon is required, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the NFS lock daemon is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.lockd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.lockd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'NFS lock' daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.lockd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000143" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the NFS Stat Daemon</title>
<description>If the system does not require access to NFS (Network File System) file shares or is not acting as an NFS server, then support for NFS is non-essential and NFS services must be disabled. NFS is a network file system protocol supported by Unix-like operating systems. Enabling any service increases the attack surface for an intruder. By disabling unnecessary services, the attack surface is minimized.</description>
<check>If the NFS stat daemon is required, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the NFS stat daemon is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.statd.notify<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.statd.notify" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'NFS stat' daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.statd.notify<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000155" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure a Firewall to Deny Access by Default</title>
<description>An approved firewall must be installed and enabled to work in concert with the Mac OS X Application Firewall. When configured correctly, firewalls protect computers from network attacks by blocking or limiting access to open network ports.</description>
<check>The system firewall must be configured with a default-deny policy. Ask the SA or ISSO if an approved firewall is loaded on the system. The recommended system is the McAfee HBSS.<p/><p/>If there is no firewall installed on the system, this is a finding. <p/><p/>If there is a firewall installed and it is not configured with a default deny policy, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Install an approved HBSS or firewall solution onto the system and configure it with a default-deny policy.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000471" nist="AOSX-10-000170" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Privileged Commands</title>
<description>Misuse of privileged functions, either intentionally or unintentionally by authorized users, or by unauthorized external entities that have compromised information system accounts, is a serious and ongoing concern and can have significant adverse impacts on organizations. Auditing the use of privileged functions is one way to detect such misuse, and identify the risk from insider threats and the advanced persistent threat.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Privileged activities are logged by way of the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000048" srgid="SRG-OS-000023" nist="AOSX-10-000185" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Display a Consent to Monitoring Banner Message</title>
<description>Display of a standardized and approved use notification before granting access to the operating system ensures privacy and security notification verbiage used is consistent with applicable federal laws, Executive Orders, directives, policies, regulations, standards, and guidance.<p/><p/>System use notifications are required only for access via logon interfaces with human users and are not required when such human interfaces do not exist.<p/><p/>The banner must be formatted in accordance with DTM-08-060.</description>
<check>The policy banner will show if a PolicyBanner.rtf or PolicyBanner.rtfd exists in the /Library/Security folder. Run this command to show the contents of that folder:<p/><p/>/bin/ls -l /Library/Security/PolicyBanner.rtf*<p/><p/>If neither PolicyBanner.rtf nor PolicyBanner.rtfd exists, this is a finding.<p/><p/>The banner text of the document MUST read:<p/><p/>"You are accessing a U.S. Government (USG) Information System (IS) that is provided for USG-authorized use only. By using this IS (which includes any device attached to this IS), you consent to the following conditions:<p/>-The USG routinely intercepts and monitors communications on this IS for purposes including, but not limited to, penetration testing, COMSEC monitoring, network operations and defense, personnel misconduct (PM), law enforcement (LE), and counterintelligence (CI) investigations.<p/>-At any time, the USG may inspect and seize data stored on this IS.<p/>-Communications using, or data stored on, this IS are not private, are subject to routine monitoring, interception, and search, and may be disclosed or used for any USG authorized purpose.<p/>-This IS includes security measures (e.g., authentication and access controls) to protect USG interests--not for your personal benefit or privacy.<p/>-Notwithstanding the above, using this IS does not constitute consent to PM, LE or CI investigative searching or monitoring of the content of privileged communications, or work product, related to personal representation or services by attorneys, psychotherapists, or clergy, and their assistants. Such communications and work product are private and confidential. See User Agreement for details."<p/><p/>If the text is not worded exactly this way, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Create a RTF formatted file containing the required text. Name the file PolicyBanner.rtf or PolicyBanner.rtfd and place it in /Library/Security/</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000048" srgid="SRG-OS-000023" nist="AOSX-10-000186" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Create a Consent to Monitoring Banner Message</title>
<description>Display of a standardized and approved use notification before granting access to the operating system ensures privacy and security notification verbiage used is consistent with applicable federal laws, Executive Orders, directives, policies, regulations, standards, and guidance.<p/><p/>System use notifications are required only for access via logon interfaces with human users and are not required when such human interfaces do not exist.<p/><p/>The banner must be formatted in accordance with DTM-08-060.</description>
<check>For systems that allow remote access through SSH, run the following command to ensure that /etc/banner exists:<p/><p/>/bin/ls -l /etc/banner<p/><p/>If /etc/banner does not exist, this is a finding.<p/><p/>The banner text of the document MUST read:<p/><p/>"You are accessing a U.S. Government (USG) Information System (IS) that is provided for USG-authorized use only. By using this IS (which includes any device attached to this IS), you consent to the following conditions:<p/>-The USG routinely intercepts and monitors communications on this IS for purposes including, but not limited to, penetration testing, COMSEC monitoring, network operations and defense, personnel misconduct (PM), law enforcement (LE), and counterintelligence (CI) investigations.<p/>-At any time, the USG may inspect and seize data stored on this IS.<p/>-Communications using, or data stored on, this IS are not private, are subject to routine monitoring, interception, and search, and may be disclosed or used for any USG authorized purpose.<p/>-This IS includes security measures (e.g., authentication and access controls) to protect USG interests--not for your personal benefit or privacy.<p/>-Notwithstanding the above, using this IS does not constitute consent to PM, LE or CI investigative searching or monitoring of the content of privileged communications, or work product, related to personal representation or services by attorneys, psychotherapists, or clergy, and their assistants. Such communications and work product are private and confidential. See User Agreement for details."<p/><p/>If the text is not worded exactly this way, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For systems that allow remote access through SSH, create a plain text file containing the required text and save it as /etc/banner.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000048" srgid="SRG-OS-000023" nist="AOSX-10-000187" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the SSH Daemon to Display a Consent to Monitoring Banner Message</title>
<description>Display of a standardized and approved use notification before granting access to the operating system ensures privacy and security notification verbiage used is consistent with applicable federal laws, Executive Orders, directives, policies, regulations, standards, and guidance.<p/><p/>System use notifications are required only for access via logon interfaces with human users and are not required when such human interfaces do not exist.<p/><p/>The banner must be formatted in accordance with DTM-08-060.</description>
<check>For systems that allow remote access through SSH, run the following command to ensure that a banner is displayed before granting access:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/grep Banner /etc/ssh/sshd_config<p/><p/>If the sshd Banner configuration option does not point to a file, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For systems that allow remote access through SSH, modify the /etc/ssh/sshd_config file to add or update the following line:<p/><p/>Banner /etc/issue</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001384" srgid="SRG-OS-000228" nist="AOSX-10-000195" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Display a Consent to Monitoring Banner Message</title>
<description>Display of a standardized and approved use notification before granting access to the operating system ensures privacy and security notification verbiage used is consistent with applicable federal laws, Executive Orders, directives, policies, regulations, standards, and guidance.<p/><p/>System use notifications are required only for access via logon interfaces with human users and are not required when such human interfaces do not exist.<p/><p/>The banner must be formatted in accordance with DTM-08-060.</description>
<check>The policy banner will show if a PolicyBanner.rtf or PolicyBanner.rtfd exists in the /Library/Security folder. Run this command to show the contents of that folder:<p/><p/>/bin/ls -l /Library/Security/PolicyBanner.rtf*<p/><p/>If neither PolicyBanner.rtf nor PolicyBanner.rtfd exists, this is a finding. <p/><p/>The banner text of the document MUST read:<p/><p/>"You are accessing a U.S. Government (USG) Information System (IS) that is provided for USG-authorized use only. By using this IS (which includes any device attached to this IS), you consent to the following conditions:<p/>-The USG routinely intercepts and monitors communications on this IS for purposes including, but not limited to, penetration testing, COMSEC monitoring, network operations and defense, personnel misconduct (PM), law enforcement (LE), and counterintelligence (CI) investigations.<p/>-At any time, the USG may inspect and seize data stored on this IS.<p/>-Communications using, or data stored on, this IS are not private, are subject to routine monitoring, interception, and search, and may be disclosed or used for any USG authorized purpose.<p/>-This IS includes security measures (e.g., authentication and access controls) to protect USG interests--not for your personal benefit or privacy.<p/>-Notwithstanding the above, using this IS does not constitute consent to PM, LE or CI investigative searching or monitoring of the content of privileged communications, or work product, related to personal representation or services by attorneys, psychotherapists, or clergy, and their assistants.  Such communications and work product are private and confidential. See User Agreement for details."<p/><p/>If the text is not worded exactly this way, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Create a RTF formatted file containing the required text.  Name the file PolicyBanner.rtf or PolicyBanner.rtfd and place it in /Library/Security/</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000470" nist="AOSX-10-000200" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Successful and Unsuccessful Logins</title>
<description>An attacker might attempt to log in as an authorized user, through stolen credentials, unpatched exploits, or brute force attempts to guess a valid username and password. If a user is attempting to log in to a system at an unusual time, or if there are many failed attempts, there is a possibility that the system is the target of an attack. Auditing logon events mitigates this risk by recording all logon attempts, successful and unsuccessful, to the system.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Logon events are logged by way of the 'aa' flag.  If 'aa' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,aa/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001464" srgid="SRG-OS-000254" nist="AOSX-10-000230" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Enable the Audit Daemon</title>
<description>If auditing is enabled late in the startup process, the actions of some start-up processes may not be audited. Some audit systems also maintain state information only available if auditing is enabled before a given process is created.</description>
<check>To check if the audit service is running, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl list | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.auditd<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, the audit service is not running and this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To enable the audit service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl load -w /System/Library/LaunchDaemons/com.apple.auditd.plist</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000169" srgid="SRG-OS-000062" nist="AOSX-10-000240" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log DoD Mandated Events</title>
<description>Without the capability to generate audit records, it would be difficult to establish, correlate, and investigate the events relating to an incident, or identify those responsible for one. DoD has defined the list of events for which the operating system will provide an audit record generation capability as the following: <p/><p/>(i) Successful and unsuccessful attempts to access, modify, or delete privileges, security objects, security levels, or categories of information (e.g., classification levels);<p/><p/>(ii) Access actions, such as successful and unsuccessful logon attempts, privileged activities or other system level access, starting and ending time for user access to the system, concurrent logons from different workstations, successful and unsuccessful accesses to objects, all program initiations, and all direct access to the information system;<p/><p/>(iii) All account creations, modifications, disabling, and terminations; and <p/><p/>(iv) All kernel module load, unload, and restart actions.</description>
<check>The options to configure the audit daemon are located in the /etc/security/audit_control file.  To view the current settings, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>If the 'lo', 'ad', and 'aa' options are not set, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To set the audit flags to the recommended setting, run the following command to add the flags 'lo', 'ad', and 'aa' all at once:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,lo,ad,aa/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000476" nist="AOSX-10-000245" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Account Creation, Modification, Disablement, and Deletion</title>
<description>Account creations and account modifications such as disablement and termination, can all be signs of an intrusion and should be audited. Once an attacker establishes access to a system, the attacker may attempt to create an account to reestablish access at a later time. The attacker may also attempt to modify accounts in an attempt to change an existing account's privileges or disable or delete accounts in a denial-of-service attack. Auditing of account creation, modification, disabling, and termination events mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Privileged access, including the creation, modification, and deletion of local user accounts, is logged via the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001849" srgid="SRG-OS-000341" nist="AOSX-10-000295" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Retain Data for 7 Days or Longer</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to require that records are kept for 7 days or longer before deletion when there is no central audit record storage facility. When expire-after is set to 7d, the audit service will not delete audit logs until the log data is at least 7 days old.</description>
<check>The check displays the amount of time the audit system is configured to retain audit log files. The audit system will not delete logs until the specified condition has been met. To view the current setting, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^expire-after /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>If this returns no results, or does not contain 7d or a larger value, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Edit the /etc/security/audit_control file, and change the value for 'expire-after' to the amount of time audit logs should be kept for the system. Use the following command to set the 'expire-after' value to '7d':<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/.*expire-after.*/expire-after:7d/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001855" srgid="SRG-OS-000343" nist="AOSX-10-000305" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Warn Administrators if Free Disk Space is below 25%</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to require a minimum percentage of free disk space in order to run. This ensures that audit will notify the administrator that action is required to free up more disk space for audit logs.<p/><p/>When minfree is set to 25%, security personnel are notified immediately when the storage volume is 75% full and are able to plan for audit record storage capacity expansion.</description>
<check>The check displays the '% free' to leave available for the system. The audit system will not write logs if the volume has less than this percentage of free disk space. To view the current setting, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^minfree /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>If this returns no results, or does not contain 25, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Edit the /etc/security/audit_control file, and change the value for 'minfree' to 25. Use the following command to set the 'minfree' value to '25%':<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/.*minfree.*/minfree:25/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001858" srgid="SRG-OS-000344" nist="AOSX-10-000310" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Print Auditing Daemon Failures to the Console</title>
<description>The audit service should be configured to immediately print messages to the console or email administrator users when an auditing failure occurs. It is critical for the appropriate personnel to be aware if a system is at risk of failing to process audit logs as required. Without a real-time alert, security personnel may be unaware of an impending failure of the audit capability and system operation may be adversely affected.</description>
<check>By default, auditd only logs errors to syslog. To see if audit has been configured to print error messages to the console, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep logger /etc/security/audit_warn<p/><p/>If the argument '-s' is missing, or if audit_warn has not been otherwise modified to print errors to the console or send email alerts to the SA and ISSO, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make auditd log errors to standard error as well as syslogd, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/logger -p/logger -s -p/' /etc/security/audit_warn; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001891" srgid="SRG-OS-000355" nist="AOSX-10-000330" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Use an Authorized Time Server</title>
<description>Inaccurate time stamps make it more difficult to correlate events and can lead to an inaccurate analysis. Determining the correct time a particular event occurred on a system is critical when conducting forensic analysis and investigating system events. Sources outside of the configured acceptable allowance (drift) may be inaccurate. <p/><p/>Synchronizing internal information system clocks provides uniformity of time stamps for information systems with multiple system clocks and systems connected over a network. <p/><p/>Organizations should consider endpoints that may not have regular access to the authoritative time server (e.g., mobile, teleworking, and tactical endpoints).</description>
<check>The Network Time Protocol (NTP) service must be enabled on all networked systems. To check if the service is running, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl list | grep org.ntp.ntpd<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding.<p/><p/>To ensure that an authorized NTP server is configured, run the following command or examine /etc/ntp.conf:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^server /etc/ntp.conf<p/><p/>Only approved time servers should be configured for use. If no server is configured, or if an unapproved time server is in use, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To enable the NTP service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl load -w /System/Library/LaunchDaemons/org.ntp.ntpd.plist<p/><p/>To configure one or more time servers for use, edit /etc/ntp.conf and enter each hostname or ip address on a separate line, prefixing each one with the keyword "server".</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000331" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Logs are Owned By Root</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log files with the correct ownership to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log files are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check the ownership of the audit log files, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -le $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}') | grep -v current<p/><p/>The results should show the owner (third column) to be root. If not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log file that returns an incorrect owner, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chown root [audit log file]<p/><p/>[audit log file] is the full path to the log file in question.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000332" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Log Folders are Owned By Root</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log files with the correct ownership to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log files are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check the ownership of the audit log folder, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -lde $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}')<p/><p/>The results should show the owner (third column) to be root. If not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log folder that has an incorrect owner, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chown root [audit log folder]</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000333" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Logs are Group Owned By Root</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log files with the correct group-ownership to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log files are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check the group-ownership of the audit log files, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -le $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}') | /usr/bin/grep -v current<p/><p/>The results should show the group owner (fourth column) to be wheel. If not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log file that returns an incorrect group-0owner, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chgrp wheel [audit log file]<p/><p/>[audit log file] is the full path to the log file in question.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000334" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Log Folders are Group Owned by Root</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log files with the correct group-ownership to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log files are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check the group-ownership of the audit log folder, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -lde $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}')<p/><p/>The results should show the group (fourth column) to be wheel. If not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log folder that has an incorrect group, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chgrp wheel [audit log folder]</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000335" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Log Permissions are 440 or Less Permissive</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log files with the correct permissions to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log files are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check the permissions of the audit log files, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -le $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}') | /usr/bin/grep -v current<p/><p/>The results should show the permissions (first column) to be 440 or less permissive. If not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log file that returns an incorrect permission value, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chmod 440 [audit log file]<p/><p/>[audit log file] is the full path to the log file in question.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000336" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Log Folders are 700 or Less Permissive</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log folders with the correct permissions to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log folders are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check the permissions of the audit log folder, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -lde $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}')<p/><p/>The results should show the permissions (first column) to be 700 or less permissive. If not, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log folder that returns an incorrect permission value, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chmod 700 [audit log folder]</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000337" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Logs Have No ACL Permissions</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log files with the correct permissions to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log files are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check if a log file contains ACLs, run the following commands:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -le $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}') | /usr/bin/grep -v current<p/><p/>In the output from the above commands, ACLs will be listed under any file that may contain them (e.g., '0: group:admin allow list,readattr,reaadextattr,readsecurity'). If any such line exists, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log file that contains ACLs, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chmod -N [audit log file]</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000162" srgid="SRG-OS-000057" nist="AOSX-10-000338" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure Audit Log Folders Have No ACL Permissions</title>
<description>The audit service must be configured to create log folders with the correct permissions to prevent normal users from reading audit logs. Audit logs contain sensitive data about the system and about users. If log folders are set to only be readable and writable by root or administrative users with sudo, the risk is mitigated.</description>
<check>To check if a log folder contains ACLs, run the following commands:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -lde $(/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep '^dir' /etc/security/audit_control | awk -F: '{print $2}')<p/><p/>In the output from the above commands, ACLs will be listed under any folder that may contain them (e.g., '0: group:admin allow list,readattr,reaadextattr,readsecurity'). If any such line exists, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log folder that contains ACLs, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chmod -N [audit log folder]</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-001749" srgid="SRG-OS-000366" nist="AOSX-10-000430" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure the Security Assessment Policy Subsystem is Enabled</title>
<description>Any changes to the hardware, software, and/or firmware components of the information system and/or application can potentially have significant effects on the overall security of the system.<p/><p/>Accordingly, software defined by the organization as critical software must be signed with a certificate that is recognized and approved by the organization.</description>
<check>To check the status of the Security assessment policy subsystem, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/spctl --status | /usr/bin/grep enabled<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To enable the Security assessment policy subsystem, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/spctl --master-enable</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001499" srgid="SRG-OS-000259" nist="AOSX-10-000435" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Ensure System Integrity Protection is Enabled</title>
<description>File permissions should be compared against the default set of permissions that were set at the time of the initial install. Changes to default file permissions can make the system less secure and disrupt the functionality of installed applications. Unless changes are required to harden a system, the default permissions should be kept. If the operating system were to allow any user to make changes to software libraries, then those changes might be implemented without undergoing the appropriate testing and approvals that are part of a robust change management process. Verifying that permissions remain unchanged mitigates this risk.<p/><p/>This requirement applies to operating systems with software libraries that are accessible and configurable, as in the case of interpreted languages. Software libraries also include privileged programs which execute with escalated privileges. Only qualified and authorized individuals shall be allowed to obtain access to information system components for purposes of initiating changes, including upgrades and modifications.</description>
<check>System Integrity Protection is a security feature, enabled by default, that protects certain system processes and files from being modified or tampered with. The current status of System Integrity Protection can be checked with the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/csrutil status<p/><p/>If the result does not show the following:<p/><p/>System Integrity Protection status: enabled.<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To reenable System Integrity Protection, boot the affected system into Recovery Mode, launch Terminal from the Utilities menu, and run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/csrutil enable</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000455" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Enforce Settings with a Configuration Profile</title>
<description>Configuration settings must be verified by a centrally managed system such as an MDM to ensure that they have not been changed. Configuration settings are the configurable security-related parameters of information technology products that are part of the information system. Security-related parameters are those parameters impacting the security state of the system including parameters related to meeting other security control requirements. Rather than visiting each and every system when verifying configuration changes, organizations will employ automated tools that can make changes across all systems.  This greatly increases efficiency and manageability of applications in a large scale environment.</description>
<check>To check if the computer has a configuration profile applied to the workstation, run the following command:<p/><p/>sudo /usr/bin/profiles -H<p/><p/>If there are no /usr/bin/profiles installed, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Obtain a configuration profile from an MDM or trusted provider containing the configuration settings required to be applied.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001774" srgid="SRG-OS-000370" nist="AOSX-10-000460" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure Application Whitelisting and Only Allow Whitelisted Applications to Run</title>
<description>Application Restrictions must be enabled for user accounts and configured to only allow users to execute approved applications. Utilizing a whitelist such as Application Restrictions provides a configuration management method for allowing the execution of only authorized software. Using only authorized software decreases risk by limiting the number of potential vulnerabilities.<p/><p/>The organization must identify authorized software programs and permit execution of authorized software. The process used to identify software programs that are authorized to execute on organizational information systems is commonly referred to as whitelisting.</description>
<check>To check if there is a configuration policy defined for Application Restrictions, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep "familyControlsEnabled = 1;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. Built-in applications such as FaceTime, Game Center, Mail, Contacts, Calendar, Reminders, and Messages should be evaluated against mission needs and should only appear in the list of allowed applications if specifically required.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using a configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000475" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The application FaceTime must be disabled with a configuration profile setting.</description>
<check>To check if there is a configuration policy defined for Application Restrictions, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep "familyControlsEnabled = 1;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if FaceTime is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 -B 4 "displayName = FaceTime;"<p/><p/>If anything is returned, this is a finding. Built-in applications such as FaceTime should be evaluated against mission needs and should only appear in the list of allowed applications if specifically required.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using a configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000480" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The application Game Center must be disabled with a configuration profile setting.</description>
<check>To check if Game Center is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep "GKFeatureGameCenterAllowed = 0;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Restrictions Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000490" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The application Messages must be disabled with a configuration profile setting.</description>
<check>To check if there is a configuration policy defined for Application Restrictions, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep "familyControlsEnabled = 1;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if Messages is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep -A 12 -B 4 "displayName = Messages;"<p/><p/>If anything is returned, this is a  finding. Built-in applications such as Messages should be evaluated against mission needs and should only appear in the list of allowed applications if specifically required.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using a configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000505" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The application Calendar must be disabled with a configuration profile setting.</description>
<check>To check if there is a configuration policy defined for Application Restrictions, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep "familyControlsEnabled = 1;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if Calendar is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | grep -A 2 -B 4 "displayName = Calendar;"<p/><p/>If anything is returned, this is a  finding. Built-in applications such as Calendar should be evaluated against mission needs and should only appear in the list of allowed applications if specifically required.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced a configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000507" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The application Reminders must be disabled with a configuration profile setting.</description>
<check>To check if there is a configuration policy defined for Application Restrictions, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep "familyControlsEnabled = 1;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if Reminders is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep -A 7 -B 4 "displayName = Reminders;"<p/><p/>If anything is returned, this is a  finding. Built-in applications such as Reminders should be evaluated against mission needs and should only appear in the list of allowed applications if specifically required.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using a configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000510" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The application Contacts must be disabled with a configuration profile setting.</description>
<check>To check if there is a configuration policy defined for Application Restrictions, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep "familyControlsEnabled = 1;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if Contacts is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 -B 4 "displayName = Contacts;"<p/><p/>If anything is returned, this is a  finding. Built-in applications such as Contacts should be evaluated against mission needs and should only appear in the list of allowed applications if specifically required.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using a configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000515" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The application Mail must be disabled with a configuration profile setting.</description>
<check>To check if there is a configuration policy defined for Application Restrictions, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep "familyControlsEnabled = 1;"<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if Mail is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep -A 2 -B 4 "displayName = Mail;"<p/><p/>If anything is returned, this is a  finding. Built-in applications such as Mail should be evaluated against mission needs and should only appear in the list of allowed applications if specifically required.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using a configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000520" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable iCloud and Internet Accounts Preference Panes</title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The system preference panels iCloud and Internet Accounts must be disabled.</description>
<check>Access to the iCloud and Internet Accounts preference panes must be disabled. To check if the system has the correct setting in the configuration profile, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 5 'DisabledPreferencePanes'<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if "iCloud" has been disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.preferences.icloud<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding. To check if "Internet Accounts" has been disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType  | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.preferences.internetaccounts<p/><p/>If nothing is returned, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Restrictions Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000382" srgid="SRG-OS-000096" nist="AOSX-10-000530" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent the System from Sending Diagnostic Data to Apple</title>
<description>In order to prevent unauthorized connection of devices, unauthorized transfer of information, or unauthorized tunneling (i.e., embedding of data types within data types), organizations must disable or restrict unused or unnecessary physical and logical ports/protocols on information systems.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services provided by default may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations. Additionally, it is sometimes convenient to provide multiple services from a single component (e.g., VPN and IPS); however, doing so increases risk over limiting the services provided by any one component. <p/><p/>To support the requirements and principles of least functionality, the operating system must support the organizational requirements providing only essential capabilities and limiting the use of ports, protocols, and/or services to only those required, authorized, and approved to conduct official business or to address authorized quality of life issues.<p/><p/>Sending diagnostic and usage data to Apple must be disabled.</description>
<check>Sending diagnostic &amp; usage data to Apple must be disabled.<p/><p/>The setting is found in System Preferences &gt;&gt; Security &amp; Privacy &gt;&gt; Privacy &gt;&gt; Diagnostics &amp; Usage.<p/><p/>If the box that says 'Send diagnostic &amp; usage data to Apple' is checked, this is a finding.<p/><p/>To check if a configuration profile is configured to enforce this setting, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep AutoSubmit<p/><p/>If AutoSubmit is not set to '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>The setting "Send diagnostic &amp; usage data to Apple" is found in System Preferences &gt;&gt; Security &amp; Privacy &gt;&gt; Privacy &gt;&gt; Diagnostics &amp; Usage.<p/><p/>Uncheck the box that says 'Send diagnostic &amp; usage data to Apple.'<p/><p/>To apply the setting from the command line, run the following commands:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/defaults read "/Library/Application Support/CrashReporter/DiagnosticMessagesHistory.plist" AutoSubmit<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults write "/Library/Application Support/CrashReporter/DiagnosticMessagesHistory.plist" AutoSubmit -bool false<p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/chmod 644 /Library/Application\ Support/CrashReporter/DiagnosticMessagesHistory.plist<p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/chgrp admin /Library/Application\ Support/CrashReporter/DiagnosticMessagesHistory.plist<p/><p/>This setting can be enforced using the "Security Privacy Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000531" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the 'Find My Mac' Service</title>
<description>In order to prevent unauthorized connection of devices, unauthorized transfer of information, or unauthorized tunneling (i.e., embedding of data types within data types), organizations must disable or restrict unused or unnecessary physical and logical ports/protocols on information systems.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services provided by default may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations. Additionally, it is sometimes convenient to provide multiple services from a single component (e.g., VPN and IPS); however, doing so increases risk over limiting the services provided by any one component. <p/><p/>To support the requirements and principles of least functionality, the operating system must support the organizational requirements providing only essential capabilities and limiting the use of ports, protocols, and/or services to only those required, authorized, and approved to conduct official business or to address authorized quality of life issues.<p/><p/>Find My Mac must be disabled.</description>
<check>To check if the 'Find My Mac' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.findmymacd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.findmymacd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'Find My Mac' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.findmymacd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000532" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the 'Find My Mac Messenger' Service</title>
<description>In order to prevent unauthorized connection of devices, unauthorized transfer of information, or unauthorized tunneling (i.e., embedding of data types within data types), organizations must disable or restrict unused or unnecessary physical and logical ports/protocols on information systems.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services provided by default may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations. Additionally, it is sometimes convenient to provide multiple services from a single component (e.g., VPN and IPS); however, doing so increases risk over limiting the services provided by any one component. <p/><p/>To support the requirements and principles of least functionality, the operating system must support the organizational requirements providing only essential capabilities and limiting the use of ports, protocols, and/or services to only those required, authorized, and approved to conduct official business or to address authorized quality of life issues.<p/><p/>Find My Mac messenger must be disabled.</description>
<check>To check if the 'Find My Mac messenger' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.findmymacmessenger<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.findmymacmessenger" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'Find My Mac messenger' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.findmymacmessenger<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000535" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Location Services</title>
<description>In order to prevent unauthorized connection of devices, unauthorized transfer of information, or unauthorized tunneling (i.e., embedding of data types within data types), organizations must disable or restrict unused or unnecessary physical and logical ports/protocols on information systems.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services provided by default may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations. Additionally, it is sometimes convenient to provide multiple services from a single component (e.g., VPN and IPS); however, doing so increases risk over limiting the services provided by any one component. <p/><p/>To support the requirements and principles of least functionality, the operating system must support the organizational requirements providing only essential capabilities and limiting the use of ports, protocols, and/or services to only those required, authorized, and approved to conduct official business or to address authorized quality of life issues.<p/><p/>Location Services must be disabled.</description>
<check>Location Services must be disabled. The setting is found in System Preferences &gt;&gt; Security &amp; Privacy &gt;&gt; Privacy &gt;&gt; Location Services.<p/><p/>If the box that says 'Enable Location Services' is checked, this is a finding.<p/><p/>To check if a configuration profile is configured to enforce this setting, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep DisableLocationServices<p/><p/>If DisableLocationServices is not set to '1', this is a finding.<p/><p/>To check if the setting was applied on the command line, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults read /private/var/db/locationd/Library/Preferences/ByHost/com.apple.locationd.`/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPHardwareDataType | /usr/bin/grep "Hardware UUID" | /usr/bin/cut -c22-57` LocationServicesEnabled</check>
<fixtext>The setting "Enable Location Services" is found in System Preferences &gt;&gt; Security &amp; Privacy &gt;&gt; Privacy &gt;&gt; Location Services.<p/><p/>Uncheck the box that says 'Enable Location Services'.<p/><p/>This setting can be enforced using the "Custom Policy" configuration profile or with the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults write /private/var/db/locationd/Library/Preferences/ByHost/com.apple.locationd.`/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPHardwareDataType | /usr/bin/grep "Hardware UUID" | /usr/bin/cut -c22-57` LocationServicesEnabled -bool false</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000545" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure Bonjour to Disable Multicast Advertisements</title>
<description>In order to prevent unauthorized connection of devices, unauthorized transfer of information, or unauthorized tunneling (i.e., embedding of data types within data types), organizations must disable or restrict unused or unnecessary physical and logical ports/protocols on information systems.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services provided by default may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations. Additionally, it is sometimes convenient to provide multiple services from a single component (e.g., VPN and IPS); however, doing so increases risk over limiting the services provided by any one component. <p/><p/>To support the requirements and principles of least functionality, the operating system must support the organizational requirements providing only essential capabilities and limiting the use of ports, protocols, and/or services to only those required, authorized, and approved to conduct official business or to address authorized quality of life issues.<p/><p/>Bonjour multicast advertising must be disabled on the system.</description>
<check>Bonjour multicast advertising must be disabled on the system. To check if multicast advertisements have been disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults read /Library/Preferences/com.apple.mDNSResponder | /usr/bin/grep NoMulticastAdvertisements<p/><p/>If nothing is returned or NoMulticastAdvertisements is not set to 1, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure Bonjour to disable multicast advertising, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults write /Library/Preferences/com.apple.mDNSResponder.plist NoMulticastAdvertisements -bool true<p/><p/>The system will need to be restarted for the update to take effect.<p/></fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-000550" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the UUCP Service</title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>The system must not have the UUCP service active.</description>
<check>To check if the 'UUCP' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.uucp<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.uucp" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'UUCP' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.uucp<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000770" srgid="SRG-OS-000109" nist="AOSX-10-000565" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Root from Logging into SSH</title>
<description>Administrator users must never log in directly as root. To assure individual accountability and prevent unauthorized access, logging in as root over a remote connection must be disabled. Administrators should only run commands as root after first authenticating with their individual user names and passwords.</description>
<check>To check if SSH has root logins enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^PermitRootLogin /etc/ssh/sshd_config<p/><p/>If there is no result, or the result is set to 'yes', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>In order to make sure that PermitRootLogin is disabled by sshd, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/^[\#]*PermitRootLogin.*/PermitRootLogin no/' /etc/ssh/sshd_config</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001941" srgid="SRG-OS-000112" nist="AOSX-10-000570" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>The SSH Version should be explicitly set to Version 2. Version 2 supports strong crypto and was rewritten from scratch to resolve several weaknesses in Version 1 that make it extremely vulnerable to attackers. The weaker crypto in Version 1 is potentially susceptible to certain forms of replay attacks. The system default is to only enable Version 2.<p/><p/>A replay attack may enable an unauthorized user to gain access to the operating system. Authentication sessions between the authenticator and the operating system validating the user credentials must not be vulnerable to a replay attack. An authentication process resists replay attacks if it is impractical to achieve a successful authentication by recording and replaying a previous authentication message.</description>
<check>To check which protocol is configured for sshd, run the following:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^Protocol /etc/ssh/sshd_config<p/><p/>If there is no result or the result is not '2', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>In order to make sure that 'Protocol 2' is used by sshd, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/.*Protocol.*/Protocol 2/' /etc/ssh/sshd_config</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001942" srgid="SRG-OS-000113" nist="AOSX-10-000575" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>The SSH Version should be explicitly set to Version 2. Version 2 supports strong crypto and was rewritten from scratch to resolve several weaknesses in Version 1 that make it extremely vulnerable to attackers. The weaker crypto in Version 1 is potentially susceptible to certain forms of replay attacks. The system default is to only enable Version 2.<p/><p/>A replay attack may enable an unauthorized user to gain access to the operating system. Authentication sessions between the authenticator and the operating system validating the user credentials must not be vulnerable to a replay attack. An authentication process resists replay attacks if it is impractical to achieve a successful authentication by recording and replaying a previous authentication message.</description>
<check>To check which protocol is configured for sshd, run the following:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^Protocol /etc/ssh/sshd_config<p/><p/>If there is no result or the result is not '2', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>In order to make sure that 'Protocol 2' is used by sshd, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/.*Protocol.*/Protocol 2/' /etc/ssh/sshd_config</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000194" srgid="SRG-OS-000071" nist="AOSX-10-000585" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Password Policy to Require at Least One Numeric Character</title>
<description>Use of a complex password helps to increase the time and resources required to compromise the password. Password complexity, or strength, is a measure of the effectiveness of a password in resisting attempts at guessing and brute-force attacks.<p/><p/>Password complexity is one factor of several that determine how long it takes to crack a password. The more complex the password, the greater the number of possible combinations that need to be tested before the password is compromised.</description>
<check>Password policy can be set with a configuration profile or the pwpolicy utility. If password policy is set with a configuration profile, run the following command to check if the system is configured to require that passwords contain at least one numeric character:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep requireAlphanumeric<p/><p/>If 'requireAlphanumeric' is not set to '1' or is undefined, this is a finding.<p/><p/>If password policy is set with the pwpolicy utility, run the following command instead:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies<p/><p/>Look for the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt;. If it does not exist, and password policy is not controlled by a directory server, this is a finding.<p/><p/>Otherwise, in the array section that follows it, there should be a &lt;dict&gt; section that contains a check &lt;string&gt; that 'matches' the variable 'policyAttributePassword' to the regular expression '(.*[0-9].*){1,}+' or to a similar expression that will ensure the password contains a character in the range 0-9 one or more times. If this check allows users to create passwords without at least one numeric character, or if no such check exists, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting may be enforced using the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile or by a directory server.<p/><p/>To set the password policy without a configuration profile, run the following command to save a copy of the current pwpolicy account policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the generated file in a text editor.<p/><p/>If the file does not yet contain any policy settings, replace &lt;dict/&gt; with &lt;dict&gt;&lt;/dict&gt;. Then, insert the following text after the opening &lt;dict&gt; tag and before the closing &lt;/dict&gt; tag.<p/><p/>The same text can also be used if the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt; is not present.<p/><p/>&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;array&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;policyAttributePassword matches '(.*[0-9].*){1,}+'&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                        &lt;string&gt;com.apple.policy.legacy.requiresNumeric&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>                                &lt;key&gt;minimumNumericCharacters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;1&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/array&gt;<p/><p/>If the file does contain policy settings, and the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt; does exist, insert the following text after the opening &lt;array&gt; tag that comes right after it:<p/><p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;policyAttributePassword matches '(.*[0-9].*){1,}+'&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                &lt;string&gt;com.apple.policy.legacy.requiresNumeric&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>                        &lt;key&gt;minimumNumericCharacters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;1&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>NOTE: Updates to password restrictions must be thoroughly evaluated in a test environment. Mistakes in configuration may block password change and local user creation operations, as well as, lock out all local users, including administrators.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000205" srgid="SRG-OS-000078" nist="AOSX-10-000590" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Password Policy to Require at Least 15 Characters</title>
<description>The minimum password length must be set to 15 characters. Password complexity, or strength, is a measure of the effectiveness of a password in resisting attempts at guessing and brute-force attacks. Password length is one factor of several that helps to determine strength and how long it takes to crack a password. The use of more characters in a password helps to exponentially increase the time and/or resources required to compromise the password.</description>
<check>To check the currently applied policies for password and accounts, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep minLength<p/><p/>The parameter minLength should be '15'.  If it is less than '15', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile.<p/><p/>NOTE: Updates to password restrictions must be thoroughly evaluated in a test environment. Mistakes in configuration may block password change and local user creation operations, as well as, lock out all local users, including administrators.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-000197" srgid="SRG-OS-000074" nist="AOSX-10-000605" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Telnet Service</title>
<description>The telnet service must be disabled, as it sends all data, including the user's password in a clear text form that can be easily intercepted and read. Passwords need to be protected at all times and encryption is the standard method for protecting passwords. If passwords are not encrypted, they can be plainly read (i.e., clear text) and easily compromised. Disabling telnet is one way to mitigate this risk.</description>
<check>To check if the 'telnet' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.telnetd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'telnet' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-002890" srgid="SRG-OS-000393" nist="AOSX-10-000690" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Telnet Service</title>
<description>The telnet service must be disabled, as it sends all data, including the user's password, in a clear text form that can be easily intercepted and read. Passwords need to be protected at all times and encryption is the standard method for protecting passwords. If passwords are not encrypted, they can be plainly read (i.e., clear text) and easily compromised. Disabling telnet is one way to mitigate this risk. Administrator users should be instructed to use an alternate service that implements cryptography such as SSH.</description>
<check>To check if the 'telnet' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.telnetd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'telnet' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-003123" srgid="SRG-OS-000394" nist="AOSX-10-000691" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Telnet Service</title>
<description>The telnet service must be disabled, as it sends all data, including the user's password, in a clear text form that can be easily intercepted and read. Passwords need to be protected at all times and encryption is the standard method for protecting passwords. If passwords are not encrypted, they can be plainly read (i.e., clear text) and easily compromised. Disabling telnet is one way to mitigate this risk. Administrator users should be instructed to use an alternate service that implements cryptography such as SSH.</description>
<check>To check if the 'telnet' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.telnetd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'telnet' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-000877" srgid="SRG-OS-000125" nist="AOSX-10-000695" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the Telnet Service</title>
<description>The telnet service must be disabled, as it sends all data, including the user's password, in a clear text form that can be easily intercepted and read. Passwords need to be protected at all times and encryption is the standard method for protecting passwords. If passwords are not encrypted, they can be plainly read (i.e., clear text) and easily compromised. Disabling telnet is one way to mitigate this risk. Administrators should be instructed to use an alternate service for remote access sessions that uses encryption, such as SSH.</description>
<check>To check if the 'telnet' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.telnetd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'telnet' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.telnetd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001749" srgid="SRG-OS-000366" nist="AOSX-10-000710" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure Gatekeeper to Only Allow Signed Applications to Run</title>
<description>Gatekeeper settings must be configured correctly to only allow the system to run applications downloaded from the Mac App Store or applications signed with a valid Apple Developer ID code. Administrator users will still have the option to override these settings on a per app basis. Gatekeeper is a security feature that ensures that applications must be digitally signed by an Apple issued certificate in order to run. Digital signatures allow Mac OS X to verify that the application has not been modified by a malicious third party.</description>
<check>To check to make sure only applications downloaded from the App Store or from Identified Developers are allowed to run, type the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep EnableAssessment<p/><p/>If 'EnableAssessment' is not set to '1', this is a finding.<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep AllowIdentifiedDevelopers<p/><p/>If 'AllowIdentifiedDevelopers' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Security Privacy Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000711" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Users from Overriding Gatekeeper Settings</title>
<description>Gatekeeper must be configured with a configuration profile in order to prevent normal users from overriding its setting. If users are allowed to disable Gatekeeper or set it to a less restrictive setting, then it is possible that malware could be introduced into the system. Gatekeeper is a security feature that ensures that applications must be digitally signed by an Apple issued certificate in order to run. Digital signatures allow Mac OS X to verify that the application has not been modified by a malicious third party.</description>
<check>To check to make sure the user cannot override Gatekeeper settings, type the following code:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep DisableOverride<p/><p/>If DisableOverride is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Security Privacy Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001133" srgid="SRG-OS-000163" nist="AOSX-10-000720" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure SSH Sessions to Log Out after 15 Minutes of Inactivity</title>
<description>SSH should be configured to log users out after a 15 minute interval of inactivity and to only wait 30 seconds before timing out login attempts. Terminating an idle session within a short time period reduces the window of opportunity for unauthorized personnel to take control of a management session enabled on the console or console port that has been left unattended. In addition, quickly terminating an idle session or an incomplete login attempt will also free up resources committed by the managed network element.</description>
<check>The SSH daemon ClientAliveInterval option must be set correctly. To check the idle timeout setting for SSH sessions, run the following:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^ClientAliveInterval /etc/ssh/sshd_config<p/><p/>If the setting is not '600', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>In order to make sure that ClientAliveInterval is set correctly, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/.*ClientAliveInterval.*/ClientAliveInterval 600/' /etc/ssh/sshd_config</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001133" srgid="SRG-OS-000163" nist="AOSX-10-000721" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure SSH Sessions to Log Out after 15 Minutes of Inactivity</title>
<description>SSH should be configured to log users out after a 15 minute interval of inactivity and to only wait 30 seconds before timing out login attempts. Terminating an idle session within a short time period reduces the window of opportunity for unauthorized personnel to take control of a management session enabled on the console or console port that has been left unattended. In addition, quickly terminating an idle session or an incomplete login attempt will also free up resources committed by the managed network element.</description>
<check>The SSH daemon ClientAliveCountMax option must be set correctly. To ensure the SSH idle timeout will occur when the 'ClientAliveCountMax' is set, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^ClientAliveCountMax /etc/ssh/sshd_config<p/><p/>If the setting is not 'ClientAliveCountMax 0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>In order to make sure that the SSH idle timeout occurs precisely when the 'ClientAliveCountMax' is set, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/.*ClientAliveCountMax.*/ClientAliveCountMax 0/' /etc/ssh/sshd_config</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001133" srgid="SRG-OS-000163" nist="AOSX-10-000722" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure SSH Sessions to Time Out Login Sessions after 30 Seconds</title>
<description>SSH should be configured to log users out after a 15 minute interval of inactivity and to only wait 30 seconds before timing out login attempts. Terminating an idle session within a short time period reduces the window of opportunity for unauthorized personnel to take control of a management session enabled on the console or console port that has been left unattended. In addition, quickly terminating an idle session or an incomplete login attempt will also free up resources committed by the managed network element.</description>
<check>The SSH daemon LoginGraceTime must be set correctly. To check the amount of time that a user can login through SSH, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^LoginGraceTime /etc/ssh/sshd_config<p/><p/>If the value is not set to '30' or less, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>In order to make sure that LoginGraceTime is configured correctly, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak 's/.*LoginGraceTime.*/LoginGraceTime 30/' /etc/ssh/sshd_config</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-002450" srgid="SRG-OS-000478" nist="AOSX-10-000750" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System Keychain to Include Approved Certificates</title>
<description>DoD-approved certificates must be installed to the System Keychain so that they will be available to all users.<p/><p/>For user certificates, each organization attains certificates from an approved, shared service provider, as required by OMB policy. For federal agencies operating a legacy public key infrastructure cross-certified with the Federal Bridge Certification Authority at medium assurance or higher, this Certification Authority will suffice. This control focuses on certificates with a visibility external to the information system and does not include certificates related to internal system operations, for example, application-specific time services.</description>
<check>To view a list of installed certificates, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/security dump-keychain | /usr/bin/grep labl | awk -F\" '{ print $4 }'<p/><p/>If this list does not contain approved certificates, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Obtain the approved DOD certificates from the appropriate authority. Use Keychain Access from /Applications/Utilities to add certificates to the System keychain.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001199" srgid="SRG-OS-000185" nist="AOSX-10-000780" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Enable FileVault on Laptops</title>
<description>FileVault Disk Encryption must be enabled. By encrypting the system hard drive, the confidentiality and integrity of any data stored on the system is ensured.<p/><p/>Information at rest refers to the state of information when it is located on a secondary storage device (e.g., disk drive and tape drive) within an organizational information system. Mobile devices, laptops, desktops, and storage devices can be either lost or stolen, and the contents of their data storage (e.g., hard drives and non-volatile memory) can be read, copied, or altered. FileVault Disk Encryption mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if FileVault 2 is enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/fdesetup status<p/><p/>If FileVault is 'Off' and the device is a laptop, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Open System Preferences &gt;&gt; Security and Privacy, and navigate to the FileVault tab. Use this panel to configure full-disk encryption.<p/><p/>Alternately, from the command line, run the following command to enable FileVault:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/fdesetup enable<p/><p/>After FileVault is initially set up, additional users can be added.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-002475" srgid="SRG-OS-000404" nist="AOSX-10-000785" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Enable FileVault on Laptops</title>
<description>FileVault Disk Encryption must be enabled. This ensures that any data stored on the hard drive will be protected by cryptographic means when the system is powered off, mitigating the risk of unauthorized modification of that data.<p/><p/>Selection of a cryptographic mechanism is based on the need to protect the integrity of organizational information. The strength of the mechanism is commensurate with the security category and/or classification of the information. Organizations have the flexibility to either encrypt all information on storage devices (i.e., full disk encryption) or encrypt specific data structures (e.g., files, records, or fields).</description>
<check>To check if FileVault 2 is enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/fdesetup status<p/><p/>If FileVault is 'Off', and the device is a laptop, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Open System Preferences &gt;&gt; Security and Privacy, and navigate to the FileVault tab. Use this panel to configure full-disk encryption.<p/><p/>Alternately, from the command line, run the following command to enable FileVault:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/fdesetup enable<p/><p/>After FileVault is initially set up, additional users can be added.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-002476" srgid="SRG-OS-000405" nist="AOSX-10-000786" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Enable FileVault on Laptops</title>
<description>FileVault Disk Encryption must be enabled. This ensures that any data stored on the hard drive will be protected by cryptographic means when the system is powered off, mitigating the risk of unauthorized disclosure of that data.<p/><p/>Selection of a cryptographic mechanism is based on the need to protect the integrity of organizational information. The strength of the mechanism is commensurate with the security category and/or classification of the information. Organizations have the flexibility to either encrypt all information on storage devices (i.e., full disk encryption) or encrypt specific data structures (e.g., files, records, or fields).</description>
<check>To check if FileVault 2 is enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/fdesetup status<p/><p/>If FileVault is 'Off', and the device is a laptop, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Open System Preferences &gt;&gt; Security and Privacy, and navigate to the FileVault tab. Use this panel to configure full-disk encryption.<p/><p/>Alternately, from the command line, run the following command to enable FileVault:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/fdesetup enable<p/><p/>After FileVault is initially set up, additional users can be added.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001233" srgid="SRG-OS-000191" nist="AOSX-10-000835" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Install an HBSS Solution for Network Monitoring</title>
<description>An approved tool for continuous network scanning must be installed and configured to run.<p/><p/>Without the use of automated mechanisms to scan for security flaws on a continuous and/or periodic basis, the operating system or other system components may remain vulnerable to the exploits presented by undetected software flaws.<p/><p/>To support this requirement, the operating system may have an integrated solution incorporating continuous scanning using HBSS and periodic scanning using other tools, as specified in the requirement.</description>
<check>Ask the SA or ISSO if an approved tool capable of continuous scanning is loaded on the system. The recommended system is the McAfee HBSS. If no such tool is installed on the system, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Install an approved HBSS solution onto the system.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000850" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable External USB Hard Drives</title>
<description>External hard drives, such as USB, must be disabled for users. USB hard drives are a potential vector for malware and can be used to exfiltrate sensitive data, if an approved data-loss prevention (DLP) solution is not installed.</description>
<check>If an approved HBSS DCM/DLP solution is installed, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To ensure external USB drives are disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep -A 3 harddisk-external<p/><p/>If the option 'eject,alert' is not set for 'harddisk-external', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Restrictions Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000862" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the usbmux Daemon</title>
<description>Connections to unauthorized iOS devices (iPhones, iPods, and iPads) open the system to possible compromise via exfiltration of system data. Disabling the usbmuxd daemon blocks connections to iOS devices.</description>
<check>To check if the usbmuxd daemon is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.usbmuxd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.usbmuxd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the usbmuxd daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.usbmuxd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000925" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Automatic Logins</title>
<description>When automatic logins are enabled, the default user account is automatically logged in at boot time without prompting the user for a password. Even if the screen is later locked, a malicious user would be able to reboot the computer in order to log in. Disabling automatic logins mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if the system if configured to automatically log in, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep DisableAutoLoginClient<p/><p/>If 'com.apple.login.mcx.DisableAutoLoginClient' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Login Window Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000930" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Not Display a List of Known Users at Login</title>
<description>The login window must be configured to prompt all users for both a username and a password. By default, the system displays a list of known users at the login screen. This gives an advantage to an attacker with physical access to the system, as the attacker would only have to guess the password for one of the listed accounts.</description>
<check>To check if the login window is configured to prompt for user name and password, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep SHOWFULLNAME<p/><p/>If there is no result, or SHOWFULLNAME is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Login Window Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000950" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Turn on Firewall Logging</title>
<description>Firewall logging must be enabled. This ensures that malicious network activity will be logged to the system.</description>
<check>If HBSS is used, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the OS X firewall has logging enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/libexec/ApplicationFirewall/socketfilterfw --getloggingmode | /usr/bin/grep on<p/><p/>If the result does not show 'on', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To enable the firewall logging, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/libexec/ApplicationFirewall/socketfilterfw --setloggingmode on</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000955" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent Bluetooth Devices from Waking the Computer</title>
<description>Bluetooth devices must not be allowed to wake the computer. If Bluetooth is not required, turn it off. If Bluetooth is necessary, disable allowing Bluetooth devices to wake the computer.</description>
<check>To check if this setting is disabled run the following two command as the primary user:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/defaults -currentHost read com.apple.Bluetooth RemoteWakeEnabled<p/><p/>/usr/bin/defaults read /Users/`whoami`/Library/Preferences/ByHost/com.apple.Bluetooth.`/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPHardwareDataType | grep "Hardware UUID" | cut -c22-57`.plist  RemoteWakeEnabled<p/><p/>If the return value is '1' for either command, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This control needs to be manually changed on the computer by opening System Preferences &gt;&gt; Bluetooth, Click Advanced, and make sure the 'Allow Bluetooth devices to wake this computer' is not checked. This control is not necessary if Bluetooth has been completely disabled.<p/><p/>The following can be run from the command line to disable Remote Wake for the current user:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/defaults write /Users/`whoami`/Library/Preferences/ByHost/com.apple.Bluetooth.`/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPHardwareDataType | /usr/bin/grep "Hardware UUID" | /usr/bin/cut -c22-57`.plist  RemoteWakeEnabled 0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000965" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Bluetooth File Sharing</title>
<description>Bluetooth sharing allows users to wirelessly transmit files between Mac OS X and Bluetooth-enabled devices, including personally owned cell phones and tablets. A malicious user might introduce viruses or malware onto the system or extract sensitive files. Disabling Bluetooth Sharing mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if Bluetooth Sharing is enabled, open up System Preferences-&gt;Sharing and verify that 'Bluetooth Sharing' is not checked 'ON'. If it is 'ON', this is a finding.<p/><p/>The following command can be run from the command line:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/defaults read /Users/`whoami`/Library/Preferences/ByHost/com.apple.Bluetooth.`/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPHardwareDataType | grep "Hardware UUID" | cut -c22-57`.plist  PrefKeyServicesEnabled<p/><p/>If the return value is '1', this is a finding<p/><p/></check>
<fixtext>To disable Bluetooth Sharing, open System Preferences-&gt;Sharing and uncheck the box next to Bluetooth Sharing. This control is not necessary if Bluetooth has been completely disabled.<p/><p/>The following can be run from the command line to disable Bluetooth Sharing for the current user:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/defaults write /Users/`whoami`/Library/Preferences/ByHost/com.apple.Bluetooth.`/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPHardwareDataType | /usr/bin/grep "Hardware UUID" | /usr/bin/cut -c22-57`.plist  PrefKeyServicesEnabled 0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000382" srgid="SRG-OS-000096" nist="AOSX-10-000975" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable the 'Remote Apple Events' Service</title>
<description>It is detrimental for operating systems to provide, or install by default, functionality exceeding requirements or mission objectives. These unnecessary capabilities or services are often overlooked and therefore may remain unsecured. They increase the risk to the platform by providing additional attack vectors.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services, provided by default, may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations (e.g., key missions, functions). <p/><p/>Examples of non-essential capabilities include, but are not limited to, games, software packages, tools, and demonstration software, not related to requirements or providing a wide array of functionality not required for every mission, but cannot be disabled.<p/><p/>Remote Apple Events must be disabled.</description>
<check>To check if the 'Remote Apple Events' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.AEServer<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.AEServer" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'Remote Apple Events' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.AEServer<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-000995" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure sudo to Request a Password Separately for Each Terminal Window</title>
<description>The sudo command must be configured to prompt for the administrator user's password at least once in each newly opened Terminal window or remote login session, as this prevents a malicious user from taking advantage of an unlocked computer or an abandoned login session to bypass the normal password prompt requirement. Without the tty_tickets option, all open local and remote login sessions would be authenticated to use sudo without a password for the duration of the configured password timeout window.</description>
<check>To check if the tty_tickets option is set for /usr/bin/sudo, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep tty_tickets /etc/sudoers<p/><p/>If there is no result, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Edit the /etc/sudoers file to contain the line:<p/><p/>Defaults tty_tickets<p/><p/>This line can be placed in the defaults section or at the end of the file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001080" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Enable the Application Firewall</title>
<description>The Application Firewall is the built-in firewall that comes with Mac OS X and must be enabled. Firewalls protect computers from network attacks by blocking or limiting access to open network ports. Application firewalls limit which applications are allowed to communicate over the network.</description>
<check>If an approved HBSS solution is installed, this is not applicable.<p/><p/>To check if the OS X firewall has been enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/libexec/ApplicationFirewall/socketfilterfw --getglobalstate<p/><p/>If the result is 'disabled', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To enable the firewall run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/libexec/ApplicationFirewall/socketfilterfw --setglobalstate on</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001110" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Change the Ownership of World Writable Directories to root or an Application Account</title>
<description>All public directories must be owned by root, the local admin user, or an application account. Directory owners have permission to delete any files contained in that directory, even if the files are owned by other user accounts. By setting the owner to an administrator or application account, regular users will not be permitted to delete each other's files.</description>
<check>To display all directories that are writable by all and not owned by root, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo find / -type d -perm +o+w -not -uid 0<p/><p/>If anything is returned, and those directories are not owned by a local admin or application account, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To change the ownership of any finding, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo find / -type d -perm +o+w -not -uid 0 -exec chown root {} \;</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001115" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>The finger service has had several security vulnerabilities in the past and is not a necessary service. It is disabled by default; enabling it would increase the attack surface of the system.</description>
<check>To check if the 'finger' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.fingerd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.fingerd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'finger' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.fingerd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001120" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Enable the Sticky Bit on World Writeable Directories</title>
<description>The sticky bit must be set on all public directories, as it prevents users with write access to the directory from deleting or renaming files that belong to other users inside it.</description>
<check>Run the following command to view all world-writable directories that do not have the sticky bit set:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo find / -type d \( -perm -0002 -a ! -perm -1000 \)<p/><p/>If anything is returned, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Run the following command to set the sticky bit on all world-writable directories:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo find / -type d \( -perm -0002 -a ! -perm -1000 \) -exec chmod +t {} \;</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001125" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Prevent New Users from Seeing the Prompt to Enter an Apple ID at Login</title>
<description>The prompt for Apple ID and iCloud must be disabled, as it might mislead new users into creating unwanted Apple IDs and iCloud storage accounts upon their first log on.</description>
<check>To check if the prompt for Apple ID and iCloud are disabled for new users, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults read /System/Library/User\ Template/English.lproj/Library/Preferences/com.apple.SetupAssistant<p/><p/>If there is no result, if it prints out that the domain "does not exist", or the results do not include 'DidSeeCloudSetup = 1 AND LastSeenCloudProductVersion = 10.11', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To ensure that the prompt for Apple ID and iCloud is disabled, run the following commands:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults write  /System/Library/User\ Template/English.lproj/Library/Preferences/com.apple.SetupAssistant DidSeeCloudSetup -bool TRUE; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/defaults write /System/Library/User\ Template/English.lproj/Library/Preferences/com.apple.SetupAssistant LastSeenCloudProductVersion '10.11'</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001130" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Identify Users that Have Logged into iCloud and Make Them Sign Out</title>
<description>Users should not sign into iCloud, as this leads to the possibility that sensitive data could be saved to iCloud storage or that users could inadvertently introduce viruses or malware previously saved to iCloud from other systems.</description>
<check>To see if any user account has configured an Apple ID for iCloud usage, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo find /Users/ -name 'MobileMeAccounts.plist' -exec /usr/bin/defaults read '{}' \;<p/><p/>If the results show any accounts listed, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This must be manually resolved.<p/><p/>With the affected user logged in, open System Preferences &gt;&gt; iCloud.<p/><p/>Choose 'Sign Out'.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001140" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable iTunes Music Sharing</title>
<description>When iTunes Music Sharing is enabled, the computer starts a network listening service that shares the contents of the user's music collection with other users in the same subnet. Unnecessary network services should always be disabled because they increase the attack surface of the system. Disabling iTunes Music Sharing mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if the iTunes music sharing is disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep disableSharedMusic<p/><p/>If 'disableSharedMusic' is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting is enforced using the "Custom Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001145" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Find and Remove all Setuid Executables that are not Vendor Installed</title>
<description>Very few of the executables that come preinstalled on Mac OS X have the setuid bit set, and administrators should never add the setuid bit to any executable that does not already have it set by the vendor. Executables with the setuid bit set allow anyone that executes them to be temporarily assigned the UID of the file owner. In practice, this almost always is the root account. While some vendors depend on this file attribute for proper operation, security problems can result if setuid is assigned to programs allowing reading and writing of files, or shell escapes, as this could lead to unprivileged users gaining privileged access to files and directories on the system.</description>
<check>If available, provide a list of setuids provided by a vendor. To list all of the files with the setuid bit set, run the following command to send all results to a file named suidfilelist.:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo find / -perm -4000 -exec /bin/ls -ldb {} \; &gt; suidfilelist<p/><p/>If any of the files listed are not documented as needing to have the setuid bit set by the vendor, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Document all of the files with the setuid bit set.<p/><p/>Remove any undocumented files.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001195" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Ignore IPv4 Source Routed Packets</title>
<description>A source-routed packet attempts to specify the network path the packet should take. If the system is not configured to block the incoming source-routed packets, an attacker can redirect the system's network traffic. Configuring the system to drop incoming source-routed IPv4 packets mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if the system is configured to accept source-routed packets, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet.ip.accept_sourceroute<p/><p/>If the value is not '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure the system to not accept source-routed packets, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet.ip.accept_sourceroute=0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001200" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Ignore IPv4 ICMP Redirect Messages</title>
<description>ICMP redirects are broadcast in order to reshape network traffic. A malicious user could craft fake redirect packets and try to force all network traffic to pass through a network sniffer. If the system is not configured to ignore these packets, it could be susceptible to this kind of attack.</description>
<check>To check if the system is configured to ignore ICMP redirect messages, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet.icmp.drop_redirect<p/><p/>If the value is not '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure the system to ignore ICMP redirect messages, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet.icmp.drop_redirect=1</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001205" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Disable IPv4 Forwarding</title>
<description>IP forwarding for IPv4 must not be enabled, as only authorized systems should be permitted to operate as routers.</description>
<check>To check if IP forwarding is enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet.ip.forwarding <p/><p/>If the values are not '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure the system to disable IP forwarding, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet.ip.forwarding=0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001206" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Disable IPv6 Forwarding</title>
<description>IP forwarding for IPv6 must not be enabled, as only authorized systems should be permitted to operate as routers.</description>
<check>To check if IP forwarding is enabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet6.ip6.forwarding<p/><p/>If the values are not '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure the system to disable IP forwarding, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet6.ip6.forwarding=0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001210" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Not Send IPv4 Redirects</title>
<description>ICMP redirects are broadcast in order to reshape network traffic. A malicious user could use the system to send fake redirect packets and try to force all network traffic to pass through a network sniffer. Disabling ICMP redirect broadcasts mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if the system is configured to send ICMP redirects, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet.ip.redirect <p/><p/>If the values are not set to '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure the system to not send ICMP redirects, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet.ip.redirect=0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001211" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Not Send IPv6 ICMP Redirects</title>
<description>ICMP redirects are broadcast in order to reshape network traffic. A malicious user could use the system to send fake redirect packets and try to force all network traffic to pass through a network sniffer. Disabling ICMP redirect broadcasts mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>To check if the system is configured to send ICMP redirects, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet6.ip6.redirect<p/><p/>If the values are not set to '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure the system to not send ICMP redirects, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet6.ip6.redirect=0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001215" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Not Forward Source Routed Packets</title>
<description>A source-routed packet attempts to specify the network path that the system should take. If the system is not configured to block the sending of source-routed packets, an attacker can redirect the system's network traffic.</description>
<check>To check if the system is configured to forward source-routed packets, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet.ip.sourceroute<p/><p/>If the value is not set to '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To configure the system to not forward source-routed packets, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet.ip.sourceroute=0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001220" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Ignore ICMP Timestamp Requests</title>
<description>ICMP Timestamp requests reveal information about the system and can be used to determine which operating system is installed. Precise time data can also be used to launch time based attacks against the system. Configuring the system to drop incoming ICMPv4 timestamp requests mitigates these risks.</description>
<check>To check if the system is configured to process ICMP timestamp requests, run the following command:<p/><p/>sysctl net.inet.icmp.timestamp<p/><p/>If the value is not set to '0', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable ICMP timestamp responses, add the following line to /etc/sysctl.conf:<p/><p/>net.inet.icmp.timestamp=0</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001235" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Unused Network Devices</title>
<description>If an unused network device is left enabled, a user might be able to activate it at a later time. Unused network devices should be disabled.</description>
<check>To list the network devices that are enabled on the system, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/networksetup -listallnetworkservices<p/><p/>A disabled device will have an asterisk in front of its name. If any listed device that is not in use is missing this asterisk, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable a network device, run the following command, substituting the name of the device in place of '&lt;networkservice&gt;':<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/networksetup -setnetworkserviceenabled '&lt;networkservice&gt;' off</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001240" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable IPv6 if Not in Use</title>
<description>Security appliances and firewalls are not always IPv6 aware, meaning that IPv6 traffic is frequently unfiltered and unprotected. If it is not in use, it should be disabled.</description>
<check>Run the following command to check if IPv6 is enabled on any network interfaces:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/networksetup -listallnetworkservices | (while read dev; do echo "$dev"; networksetup -getinfo "$dev" | /usr/bin/grep IPv6:; echo ; done)<p/><p/>If there is an enabled network interface without the setting 'IPv6: Off' and it does not require IPv6, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Run the following command to turn off IPv6 addressing for the Ethernet interface:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/networksetup -setv6off 'Ethernet'<p/><p/>Repeat this command for each enabled interface, interface names are case sensitive.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-001270" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Internet Sharing</title>
<description>In order to prevent unauthorized connection of devices, unauthorized transfer of information, or unauthorized tunneling (i.e., embedding of data types within data types), organizations must disable or restrict unused or unnecessary physical and logical ports/protocols on information systems.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services provided by default may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations. Additionally, it is sometimes convenient to provide multiple services from a single component (e.g., VPN and IPS); however, doing so increases risk over limiting the services provided by any one component. <p/><p/>To support the requirements and principles of least functionality, the operating system must support the organizational requirements providing only essential capabilities and limiting the use of ports, protocols, and/or services to only those required, authorized, and approved to conduct official business or to address authorized quality of life issues.<p/><p/>Internet Sharing must be disabled.</description>
<check>To check if the 'Internet Sharing' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep com.apple.NetworkSharing<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"com.apple.NetworkSharing" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'Internet Sharing' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/com.apple.NetworkSharing<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-001275" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable Web Sharing</title>
<description>Web Sharing is non-essential and must be disabled. Enabling any service increases the attack surface for an intruder. By disabling unnecessary services, the attack surface is minimized.</description>
<check>To check if the 'Web Sharing' service is disabled, use the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl print-disabled system | /usr/bin/grep org.apache.httpd<p/><p/>If the results do not show the following:<p/><p/>"org.apache.httpd" =&gt; true<p/><p/>this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To disable the 'Web Sharing' service, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /bin/launchctl disable system/org.apache.httpd<p/><p/>The system may need to be restarted for the update to take effect.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-002238" srgid="SRG-OS-000021" nist="AOSX-10-001324" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Lock Out Users for 15 Minutes After 3 Failed Login Attempts</title>
<description>Setting a lockout time period of 15 minutes is an effective deterrent against brute forcing that also makes allowances for legitimate mistakes by users. When three invalid logon attempts are made, the account will be locked.</description>
<check>Password policy can be set with a configuration profile or the pwpolicy utility. If password policy is set with a configuration profile, run the following command to check if the system has the correct setting for the logon reset timer:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep 'minutesUntilFailedLoginReset'<p/><p/>If 'minutesUntilFailedLoginReset is not set to '15', this is a finding.<p/><p/>If password policy is set with the pwpolicy utility, the variable names may vary depending on how the policy was set. To check if the password policy is configured to disable an account for 15 minutes after 3 unsuccessful logon attempts, run the following command to output the password policy to the screen:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies<p/><p/>Look for the line '&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;'.<p/><p/>If this does not exist, and password policy is not controlled by a directory server, this is a finding.<p/><p/>In the array that follows, there should one or more &lt;dict&gt; sections that describe policy checks. One should contain a &lt;string&gt; that allows users to log on if 'policyAttributeFailedAuthentications' is less than 'policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications'. Under policyParameters, policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications should be set to 3.<p/><p/>If 'policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications' is not set to 3, this is a finding.<p/><p/>In the same check or in another &lt;dict&gt; section, there should be a &lt;string&gt; that allows users to log on if the 'policyAttributeCurrentTime' is greater than the result of adding 15 minutes (900 seconds) to 'policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime'. The check might use a variable defined in its policyParameters section.<p/><p/>If the check does not exist or if the check adds too great an amount of time, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting may be enforced using the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile or by a directory server.<p/><p/>The following two lines within the configuration enforce lockout expiration to 15 minutes:<p/><p/>&lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/><p/>To set the password policy without a configuration profile, run the following command to save a copy of the current pwpolicy account policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the generated file in a text editor and ensure it contains the following text after the opening &lt;dict&gt; tag and before the closing &lt;/dict&gt; tag.<p/><p/>Replace &lt;dict/&gt; first with &lt;dict&gt;&lt;/dict&gt; if necessary.<p/><p/>&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;array&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/array&gt;<p/><p/>If the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt; already exists, the following text should be used instead and inserted after the first &lt;array&gt; tag that follows it:<p/><p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>NOTE: Updates to password restrictions must be thoroughly evaluated in a test environment. Mistakes in configuration may block password change and local user creation operations, as well as, lock out all local users, including administrators.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000044" srgid="SRG-OS-000021" nist="AOSX-10-001325" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Lock Out Users for 15 Minutes After 3 Failed Login Attempts</title>
<description>By limiting the number of failed logon attempts, the risk of unauthorized system access via user password guessing, otherwise known as brute forcing, is reduced. Limits are imposed by locking the account.</description>
<check>Password policy can be set with a configuration profile or the pwpolicy utility. If password policy is set with a configuration profile, run the following command to check if the system has the correct setting for the number of permitted failed logon attempts:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep 'maxFailedAttempts'<p/><p/>If 'maxFailedAttempts' is not set to '3', this is a finding.<p/><p/>If password policy is set with the pwpolicy utility, the variable names may vary depending on how the policy was set. To check if the password policy is configured to disable an account for 15 minutes after 3 unsuccessful logon attempts, run the following command to output the password policy to the screen:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies<p/><p/>Look for the line '&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;'.<p/><p/>If this does not exist, and password policy is not controlled by a directory server, this is a finding.<p/><p/>In the array that follows, there should one or more &lt;dict&gt; sections that describe policy checks. One should contain a &lt;string&gt; that allows users to log on if 'policyAttributeFailedAuthentications' is less than 'policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications'. Under policyParameters, policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications should be set to 3.<p/><p/>If 'policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications' is not set to 3, this is a finding.<p/><p/>In the same check or in another &lt;dict&gt; section, there should be a &lt;string&gt; that allows users to log on if the 'policyAttributeCurrentTime' is greater than the result of adding 15 minutes (900 seconds) to 'policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime'. The check might use a variable defined in its policyParameters section.<p/><p/>If the check does not exist or if the check adds too great an amount of time, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting may be enforced using the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile or by a directory server.<p/><p/>To set the password policy without a configuration profile, run the following command to save a copy of the current pwpolicy account policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the generated file in a text editor and ensure it contains the following text after the opening &lt;dict&gt; tag and before the closing &lt;/dict&gt; tag. Replace &lt;dict/&gt; first with &lt;dict&gt;&lt;/dict&gt; if necessary.<p/><p/>&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;array&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>                                &lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>                                &lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/array&gt;<p/><p/>If the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt; already exists, the following text should be used instead and inserted after the first &lt;array&gt; tag that follows it:<p/><p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>                        &lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;array&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>                                &lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>                                &lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/array&gt;<p/><p/>If the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt; already exists, the following text should be used instead and inserted after the first &lt;array&gt; tag that follows it:<p/><p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>                        &lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>NOTE: Updates to password restrictions must be thoroughly evaluated in a test environment. Mistakes in configuration or bugs in OS X may block password change and local user creation operations, as well as, lock out all local users, including administrators.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-002238" srgid="SRG-OS-000329" nist="AOSX-10-001326" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Lock Out Users for 15 Minutes After 3 Failed Login Attempts</title>
<description>By limiting the number of failed logon attempts, the risk of unauthorized system access via user password guessing, otherwise known as brute forcing, is reduced. Limits are imposed by locking the account. Setting a lockout expiration of 15 minutes is an effective deterrent against brute forcing that also makes allowances for legitimate mistakes by users.</description>
<check>Password policy can be set with a configuration profile or the pwpolicy utility. If password policy is set with a configuration profile, run the following command to check if the system has the correct setting for the number of permitted failed logon attempts and the logon reset timer:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep 'maxFailedAttempts\|minutesUntilFailedLoginReset'<p/><p/>If 'maxFailedAttempts' is not set to '3' and 'minutesUntilFailedLoginReset is not set to '15', this is a finding.<p/><p/>If password policy is set with the pwpolicy utility, the variable names may vary depending on how the policy was set. To check if the password policy is configured to disable an account for 15 minutes after 3 unsuccessful logon attempts, run the following command to output the password policy to the screen:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies<p/><p/>Look for the line '&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;'.<p/><p/>If this does not exist, and password policy is not controlled by a directory server, this is a finding.<p/><p/>In the array that follows, there should be one or more &lt;dict&gt; sections that describe policy checks. One should contain a &lt;string&gt; that allows users to log on if 'policyAttributeFailedAuthentications' is less than 'policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications'. Under policyParameters, policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications should be set to 3.<p/><p/>If 'policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications' is not set to 3, this is a finding.<p/><p/>In the same check or in another &lt;dict&gt; section, there should be a &lt;string&gt; that allows users to log on if the 'policyAttributeCurrentTime' is greater than the result of adding 15 minutes (900 seconds) to 'policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime'. The check might use a variable defined in its policyParameters section.<p/><p/>If the check does not exist or if the check adds too great an amount of time, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting may be enforced using the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile or by a directory server.<p/><p/>To set the password policy without a configuration profile, run the following command to save a copy of the current pwpolicy account policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the generated file in a text editor and ensure it contains the following text after the opening &lt;dict&gt; tag and before the closing &lt;/dict&gt; tag.<p/><p/>Replace &lt;dict/&gt; first with &lt;dict&gt;&lt;/dict&gt; if necessary.<p/><p/>&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;array&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/array&gt;<p/><p/>If the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryAuthentication&lt;/key&gt; already exists, the following text should be used instead and inserted after the first &lt;array&gt; tag that follows it:<p/><p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;(policyAttributeFailedAuthentications &lt; policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications) OR (policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; (policyAttributeLastFailedAuthenticationTime + autoEnableInSeconds))&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Authentication Lockout&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;autoEnableInSeconds&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;900&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyAttributeMaximumFailedAuthentications&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;3&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>NOTE: Updates to password restrictions must be thoroughly evaluated in a test environment. Mistakes in configuration or bugs in OS X may block password change and local user creation operations, as well as, lock out all local users, including administrators.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000140" srgid="SRG-OS-000047" nist="AOSX-10-001355" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the System to Shutdown if the Audit Daemon Fails</title>
<description>The audit service should shut down the computer if it is unable to audit system events. Once audit failure occurs, user and system activity is no longer recorded and malicious activity could go undetected. Audit processing failures include: software/hardware errors; failures in the audit capturing mechanisms; and audit storage capacity being reached or exceeded. Responses to audit failure depend upon the nature of the failure mode.<p/><p/>When availability is an overriding concern, other approved actions in response to an audit failure are as follows: <p/><p/>(i) If the failure was caused by the lack of audit record storage capacity, the operating system must continue generating audit records if possible (automatically restarting the audit service if necessary), overwriting the oldest audit records in a first-in-first-out manner. <p/><p/>(ii) If audit records are sent to a centralized collection server and communication with this server is lost or the server fails, the operating system must queue audit records locally until communication is restored or until the audit records are retrieved manually. Upon restoration of the connection to the centralized collection server, action should be taken to synchronize the local audit data with the collection server.</description>
<check>To view the setting for the audit control system, run the following command:<p/><p/>sudo /usr/bin/grep ^policy /etc/security/audit_control | /usr/bin/grep ahlt<p/><p/>If there is no result, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Edit the /etc/security/audit_control file, and change the value for policy to include the setting 'ahlt'. To programmatically do this, run the following command:<p/><p/>sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^policy/ s/$/,ahlt/' /etc/security/audit_control; sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="high">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-001465" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Install an Approved Antivirus Program</title>
<description>An approved anti-virus product must be installed and configured to run.<p/><p/>Malicious software can establish a base on individual desktops and servers.  Employing an automated mechanism to detect this type of software will aid in elimination of the software from the operating system.</description>
<check>Ask the SA or ISSO if an approved anti-virus solution is loaded on the system. The anti-virus solution may be bundled with an approved host-based security solution. If there is no local anti-virus solution installed on the system, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Install an approved anti-virus solution onto the system.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="low">
<ident cci="CCI-000381" srgid="SRG-OS-000095" nist="AOSX-10-002050" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Disable AirDrop</title>
<description>In order to prevent unauthorized connection of devices, unauthorized transfer of information, or unauthorized tunneling (i.e., embedding of data types within data types), organizations must disable or restrict unused or unnecessary physical and logical ports/protocols on information systems.<p/><p/>Operating systems are capable of providing a wide variety of functions and services. Some of the functions and services provided by default may not be necessary to support essential organizational operations. Additionally, it is sometimes convenient to provide multiple services from a single component (e.g., VPN and IPS); however, doing so increases risk over limiting the services provided by any one component. <p/><p/>To support the requirements and principles of least functionality, the operating system must support the organizational requirements providing only essential capabilities and limiting the use of ports, protocols, and/or services to only those required, authorized, and approved to conduct official business or to address authorized quality of life issues.<p/><p/>AirDrop must be disabled.</description>
<check>AirDrop must be disabled. To check if AirDrop has been disabled, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep DisableAirDrop<p/><p/>If DisableAirDrop is not set to '1', this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Disabling AirDrop is enforced using the "Restrictions Policy" configuration profile.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000366" srgid="SRG-OS-000480" nist="AOSX-10-002055" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title></title>
<description>Password-based authentication has become a prime target for malicious actors. Multifactor authentication using PKI technologies mitigates most, if not all, risks associated with traditional password use. (Use of username and password for last-resort emergency access to a system for maintenance is acceptable, however.)</description>
<check>Ask the SA or ISSO if an approved PKI authentication solution is implemented on the system for user logins and privileged access.<p/><p/>If a non-emergency account can log into the system or gain privileged access without a smart card, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>Implement PKI authentication using approved third-party PKI tools, to integrate with an existing directory services infrastructure or local password database, where no directory services infrastructure exists.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000477" nist="AOSX-10-002065" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Kernel Module Loading and Unloading</title>
<description>Kernel modules, called kernel extensions in Mac OS X, are compiled segments of code that are dynamically loaded into the kernel as required to support specific pieces of hardware or functionality. Privileged users are permitted to load or unload kernel extensions manually. An attacker might attempt to load a kernel extension that is known to be insecure to increase the attack surface of the system, or a user might plug in an unauthorized device that then triggers a kernel extension to be loaded. Auditing administrative actions, which include the loading or unloading of kernel extensions, mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Privileged access, including administrative use of the command line tools kextload and kextunload, is logged via the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000463" nist="AOSX-10-002070" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Changes to File Permissions</title>
<description>The permissions on a file establish which users are permitted to access or modify it. An attacker may attempt to change the permissions on a file to prevent legitimate users from accessing it or to grant additional access to an account the attacker controls. Auditing successful and unsuccessful attempts to modify security objects such as file permissions mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Changes to file permissions are logged by way of the 'fm' flag.  If 'fm' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,fm/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000464" nist="AOSX-10-002075" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Changes to File Permissions</title>
<description>The permissions on a file establish which users are permitted to access or modify it. An attacker may attempt to change the permissions on a file to prevent legitimate users from accessing it or to grant additional access to an account the attacker controls. Auditing successful and unsuccessful attempts to modify security objects such as file permissions mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Changes to file permissions are logged by way of the 'fm' flag.  If 'fm' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,fm/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000465" nist="AOSX-10-002080" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Changes to File Permissions</title>
<description>The permissions on a file establish which users are permitted to access or modify it. An attacker may attempt to change the permissions on a file to prevent legitimate users from accessing it or to grant additional access to an account the attacker controls. Auditing successful and unsuccessful attempts to modify security objects such as file permissions mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Changes to file permissions are logged by way of the 'fm' flag.  If 'fm' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,fm/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000199" srgid="SRG-OS-000076" nist="AOSX-10-002085" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Password Policy to Expire Passwords after 60 Days or Sooner</title>
<description>Any password, no matter how complex, can eventually be cracked. Therefore, passwords need to be changed periodically.<p/><p/>One method of minimizing this risk is to use complex passwords and periodically change them. If the operating system does not limit the lifetime of passwords and force users to change their passwords, there is the risk that the operating system passwords could be compromised.</description>
<check>Password policy can be set with a configuration profile or the pwpolicy utility. If password policy is set with a configuration profile, run the following command to check if the system is configured to require users to change their passwords every 60 days:<p/><p/>/usr/sbin/system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep maxPINAgeInDays<p/><p/>If 'maxPINAgeInDays' is not set to '60' or a shorter interval, or is undefined, this is a finding.<p/><p/>If password policy is set with the pwpolicy utility, run the following command instead:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies<p/><p/>Look for the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordChange&lt;/key&gt;.<p/><p/>If it does not exist, and password policy is not controlled by a directory server, this is a finding.<p/><p/>Otherwise, in the array section that follows it, there should be a &lt;dict&gt; section that contains a check &lt;string&gt; that compares the variable 'policyAttributeLastPasswordChangeTime' to the variable 'policyAttributeCurrentTime'. It may contain additional variables defined in the policyParameters section that follows it. All comparisons are done in seconds.<p/><p/>If this check allows users to log in with passwords older than 60 days, or if no such check exists, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting may be enforced using the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile or by a directory server.<p/><p/>To set the password policy without a configuration profile, run the following command to save a copy of the current pwpolicy account policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the generated file in a text editor.<p/><p/>If the file does not yet contain any policy settings, replace &lt;dict/&gt; with &lt;dict&gt;&lt;/dict&gt;.<p/><p/>If there already is a policy block that refers to password expiration, ensure it is set to 60 days.<p/><p/>If the line '&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordChange&lt;/key&gt;' is not present in the file, add the following text immediately after the opening &lt;dict&gt; tag in the file:<p/><p/>&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordChange&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;array&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; policyAttributeLastPasswordChangeTime + (policyAttributeExpiresEveryNDays * 24 * 60 * 60)&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Password Change Interval&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyAttributeExpiresEveryNDays&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;60&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/array&gt;<p/><p/>If the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordChange&lt;/key&gt; is already present in the file, the following text should be added just after the opening &lt;array&gt; tag that follows the line instead:<p/><p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;policyAttributeCurrentTime &gt; policyAttributeLastPasswordChangeTime + (policyAttributeExpiresEveryNDays * 24 * 60 * 60)&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;string&gt;Password Change Interval&lt;/string&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;dict&gt;<p/>&lt;key&gt;policyAttributeExpiresEveryNDays&lt;/key&gt;<p/>&lt;integer&gt;60&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/>&lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>NOTE: Updates to password restrictions must be thoroughly evaluated in a test environment. Mistakes in configuration may block password change and local user creation operations, as well as, lock out all local users, including administrators.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000200" srgid="SRG-OS-000077" nist="AOSX-10-002090" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Password Policy to Remember the User's Five Previous Passwords to Prevent Password Reuse</title>
<description>Password complexity, or strength, is a measure of the effectiveness of a password in resisting attempts at guessing and brute-force attacks. If the information system or application allows the user to consecutively reuse their password when that password has exceeded its defined lifetime, the end result is a password that is not changed as per policy requirements.</description>
<check>Password policy can be set with the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile or the pwpolicy utility. If password policy is set with a configuration profile, run the following command to check if the system is configured to require that users cannot reuse one of their five previously used passwords:<p/><p/>system_profiler SPConfigurationProfileDataType | /usr/bin/grep pinHistory<p/><p/>If 'pinHistory' is not set to '5' or higher, or is undefined, this is a finding.<p/><p/>If password policy is set with the pwpolicy utility, run the following command instead:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies<p/><p/>Look for the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt;. If it does not exist, and password policy is not controlled by a directory server, this is a finding.<p/><p/>Otherwise, in the array section that follows it, there should be a &lt;dict&gt; section that contains a check &lt;string&gt; such as '&lt;string&gt;none policyAttributePasswordHashes in policyAttributePasswordHistory&lt;/string&gt;'. This searches for the hash of the user-entered password in the list of previous password hashes. In the policyParameters section that follows it, policyAttributePasswordHistoryDepth must be set to 5 or greater. If this parameter is not set to 5 or greater, or if no such check exists, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>This setting may be enforced using the "Passcode Policy" configuration profile or by a directory server.<p/><p/>To set the password policy without a configuration profile, run the following command to save a copy of the current pwpolicy account policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy getaccountpolicies | tail -n +2 &gt; pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>Open the generated file in a text editor. If the file does not yet contain any policy settings, replace &lt;dict/&gt; with &lt;dict&gt;&lt;/dict&gt;. If there already is a policy block that refers to password history, ensure it is set to 5. If the line '&lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt;' is not present in the file, add the following text immediately after the opening &lt;dict&gt; tag in the file:<p/><p/>        &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>        &lt;array&gt;<p/>                &lt;dict&gt;<p/>                        &lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                        &lt;string&gt;none policyAttributePasswordHashes in policyAttributePasswordHistory&lt;/string&gt;<p/>                        &lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                        &lt;string&gt;Password History&lt;/string&gt;<p/>                        &lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                        &lt;dict&gt;<p/>                                &lt;key&gt;policyAttributePasswordHistoryDepth&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                                &lt;integer&gt;5&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>                        &lt;/dict&gt;<p/>                &lt;/dict&gt;<p/>        &lt;/array&gt;<p/><p/>If the line &lt;key&gt;policyCategoryPasswordContent&lt;/key&gt; is already present in the file, the following text should be added just after the opening &lt;array&gt; tag that follows the line instead:<p/><p/>        &lt;dict&gt;<p/>                &lt;key&gt;policyContent&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                &lt;string&gt;none policyAttributePasswordHashes in policyAttributePasswordHistory&lt;/string&gt;<p/>                &lt;key&gt;policyIdentifier&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                &lt;string&gt;Password History&lt;/string&gt;<p/>                &lt;key&gt;policyParameters&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                &lt;dict&gt;<p/>                        &lt;key&gt;policyAttributePasswordHistoryDepth&lt;/key&gt;<p/>                        &lt;integer&gt;5&lt;/integer&gt;<p/>                &lt;/dict&gt;<p/>        &lt;/dict&gt;<p/><p/>After saving the file and exiting to the command prompt, run the following command to load the new policy file:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/pwpolicy setaccountpolicies pwpolicy.plist<p/><p/>NOTE: Updates to password restrictions must be thoroughly evaluated in a test environment. Mistakes in configuration may block password change and local user creation operations, as well as, lock out all local users, including administrators.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000466" nist="AOSX-10-002095" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Changes to File Permissions</title>
<description>The permissions on a file establish which users and groups are permitted to access or modify it. An attacker may attempt to change the permissions on a file to prevent legitimate users from accessing it or to grant additional access to an account the attacker controls. Auditing successful and unsuccessful attempts to modify security objects such as file permissions mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Changes to file permissions are logged by way of the 'fm' flag.  If 'fm' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000064" nist="AOSX-10-002100" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Administrative Commands and Logins</title>
<description>Frequently, an attacker that successfully gains access to a system has only gained access to an account with limited privileges, such as a guest account or a service account. The attacker must attempt to change to another user account with normal or elevated privileges in order to proceed. Auditing successful and unsuccessful attempts to elevate privileges mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>The options to configure the audit daemon are located in the /etc/security/audit_control file. To view the current settings, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>If the 'lo', 'ad', and 'aa' options are not set, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To set the audit flags to the recommended setting, run the following command to add the flags 'lo', 'ad', and 'aa' all at once:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,lo,ad,aa/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001314" srgid="SRG-OS-000206" nist="AOSX-10-002105" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Change the Ownership of System Log Files to root and Group Ownership to wheel or admin</title>
<description>System logs should only be readable by root or admin users. System logs frequently contain sensitive information that could be used by an attacker. Setting the correct owner mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>Log files are controlled by newsyslog and aslmanager.<p/><p/>These commands check for log files that exist on the system and print out the log with corresponding ownership. Run them from inside /var/log:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo stat -f '%Su:%Sg:%N' $(/usr/bin/grep -v '^#' /etc/newsyslog.conf | awk '{ print $1 }') 2&gt; /dev/null<p/>/usr/bin/sudo stat -f '%Su:%Sg:%N' $(/usr/bin/grep -e '^&gt;' /etc/asl.conf /etc/asl/* | awk '{ print $2 }') 2&gt; /dev/null<p/><p/>If there are any system log files that are not owned by root and group-owned by wheel or admin, this is a finding. Service logs may be owned by the service user account or group.</check>
<fixtext>For any log file that returns an incorrect owner or group value, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chown root:wheel [log file]<p/><p/>[log file] is the full path to the log file in question. If the file is managed by newsyslog, find the configuration line in the directory /etc/newsyslog.d/ or the file /etc/newsyslog.conf and ensure that the owner:group column is set to root:wheel or the appropriate service user account and group. If the file is managed by aslmanager, find the configuration line in the directory /etc/asl/ or the file /etc/asl.conf and ensure that uid and gid options are either not present or are set to a service user account and group respectively.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001314" srgid="SRG-OS-000206" nist="AOSX-10-002106" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Change the Permissions of System Log Files to 640 or Less Permissive</title>
<description>System logs should only be readable by root or admin users. System logs frequently contain sensitive information that could be used by an attacker. Setting the correct permissions mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>These commands check for log files that exist on the system and print out the log with corresponding permissions. Run them from inside /var/log:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo stat -f '%A:%N' $(/usr/bin/grep -v '^#' /etc/newsyslog.conf | awk '{ print $1 }') 2&gt; /dev/null<p/>/usr/bin/sudo stat -f '%A:%N' $(/usr/bin/grep -e '^&gt;' /etc/asl.conf /etc/asl/* | awk '{ print $2 }') 2&gt; /dev/null<p/><p/>The correct permissions on log files should be '640' or less permissive for system logs. Any file with more permissive settings is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log file that returns an incorrect permission value, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chmod 640 [log file]<p/><p/>[log file] is the full path to the log file in question. If the file is managed by newsyslog, find the configuration line in the directory /etc/newsyslog.d/ or the file /etc/newsyslog.conf and edit the mode column to be 640 or less permissive. If the file is managed by aslmanager, find the configuration line in the directory /etc/asl/ or the file /etc/asl.conf and add or edit the mode option to be 'mode=0640' or less permissive.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001314" srgid="SRG-OS-000206" nist="AOSX-10-002107" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Change the Permissions of System Log Files to Remove ACLs</title>
<description>System logs should only be readable by root or admin users. System logs frequently contain sensitive information that could be used by an attacker. Setting the correct ACLs mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>These commands check for log files that exist on the system and print out the list of ACLs if there are any.<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -ld@ $(/usr/bin/grep -v '^#' /etc/newsyslog.conf | awk '{ print $1 }') 2&gt; /dev/null<p/>/usr/bin/sudo ls -ld@ $(/usr/bin/grep -e '^&gt;' /etc/asl.conf /etc/asl/* | awk '{ print $2 }') 2&gt; /dev/null<p/><p/>ACLs will be listed under any file that may contain them, i.e., '0: group:admin allow list,readattr,reaadextattr,readsecurity'.<p/><p/>If any system log file contains this information, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>For any log file that returns an ACL, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo chmod -N [log file]<p/><p/>[log file] is the full path to the log file in question.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-001814" srgid="SRG-OS-000365" nist="AOSX-10-002110" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Changes to File Permissions and Unsuccessful Attempts to Read and Write Files</title>
<description>By auditing access restriction enforcement, changes to application and OS configuration files can be audited. Without auditing the enforcement of access restrictions, it will be difficult to identify attempted attacks and an audit trail will not be available for forensic investigation.<p/><p/>Enforcement actions are the methods or mechanisms used to prevent unauthorized changes to configuration settings. Enforcement action methods may be as simple as denying access to a file based on the application of file permissions (access restriction). Audit items may consist of lists of actions blocked by access restrictions or changes identified after the fact.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Enforcement actions are logged by way of the 'fm' flag, which audits permission changes, and '-fr' and '-fw', which denote failed attempts to read or write to a file. If 'fm', '-fr', and '-fw' are not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To set the audit flags to the recommended setting, run the following command to add the flags 'lo', 'ad', and 'aa' all at once:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,lo,ad,aa/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-002884" srgid="SRG-OS-000392" nist="AOSX-10-002115" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Administrative Commands</title>
<description>If events associated with non-local administrative access or diagnostic sessions are not logged, a major tool for assessing and investigating attacks would not be available.<p/><p/>This requirement addresses auditing-related issues associated with maintenance tools used specifically for diagnostic and repair actions on organizational information systems.<p/><p/>Non-local maintenance and diagnostic activities are those activities conducted by individuals communicating through a network, either an external network (e.g., the Internet) or an internal network. Local maintenance and diagnostic activities are those activities carried out by individuals physically present at the information system or information system component and not communicating across a network connection. <p/><p/>This requirement applies to hardware/software diagnostic test equipment or tools. This requirement does not cover hardware/software components that may support information system maintenance, yet are a part of the system, for example, the software implementing "ping", "ls", "ipconfig", or the hardware and software implementing the monitoring port of an Ethernet switch.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Administrative actions and changes to configuration settings are logged by way of the 'ad' flag. If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-002234" srgid="SRG-OS-000327" nist="AOSX-10-002120" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Administrative Commands</title>
<description>Misuse of privileged functions, either intentionally or unintentionally by authorized users, or by unauthorized external entities that have compromised information system accounts, is a serious and ongoing concern and can have significant adverse impacts on organizations. Auditing the use of privileged functions is one way to detect such misuse, and identify the risk from insider threats and the advanced persistent threat.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Privileged access is logged via the 'ad' flag.  If 'ad' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,ad/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

<Rule severity="medium">
<ident cci="CCI-000172" srgid="SRG-OS-000462" nist="AOSX-10-002125" />
<status>Applicable - Configurable</status>
<title>Configure the Audit Daemon to Log Logins</title>
<description>Frequently, an attacker that successfully gains access to a system has only gained access to an account with limited privileges, such as a guest account or a service account. The attacker must attempt to change to another user account with normal or elevated privileges in order to proceed. Auditing successful and unsuccessful attempts to switch to another user account mitigates this risk.</description>
<check>In order to view the currently configured flags for the audit daemon, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo /usr/bin/grep ^flags /etc/security/audit_control<p/><p/>Attempts to log in as another user are logged by way of the 'lo' flag. If 'lo' is not listed in the result of the check, this is a finding.</check>
<fixtext>To make sure the appropriate flags are enabled for auditing, run the following command:<p/><p/>/usr/bin/sudo sed -i.bak '/^flags/ s/$/,lo/' /etc/security/audit_control; /usr/bin/sudo /usr/sbin/audit -s<p/><p/>A text editor may also be used to implement the required updates to the /etc/security/audit_control file.</fixtext>
</Rule>

</Benchmark>